1983年
- 这是410档案
- 好的谢谢
我不知被派出去海外多少次了
这是我在越南见过最棒的马子
这些女人每天都有人光顾
我们躺在安全的地方，尽情修身
直到有人写信给他妈妈
漏了口风…哟真是他妈的
结果我们的那些国会议员们
认为我们实在太轻松了
所以陆战队员将不再有短假期
命令两旅的陆战队，加速回战区
我们得到一些性病…毛湿
所以，对女性就会产生一种
恶劣的态度了
很可怕吧？小孩！那是事实！
我不喜欢士兵小子！
你在说什么？
你想要操那些妞
你就必须狠一点，笨蛋！
看来老兄你是很有经验的人！
那是什么意思？浑虫！
那是给你个好忠告！
我又狠又累
我嚼跌丝和泡尿在汽油弹上
我可以在两百码外射中头湿屁股
所以你去找别人的麻烦
否则我会叫你头破血流
当你的睾丸塞进你口中时
- 看你怎么神气！
- 哦！狗屎！
替我拿一下！我想战争已开始了
你何不乖乖坐着流些血
免得尝到真正的苦头
也许我先来砍这怪物几下混蛋！
杀了他！
还有，在曼谷的那个妞
真的是功夫绝顶，我发誓！
多谢你的证供，里兹警官
海威士官
醉酒和目无法纪当众打架
你洒尿在警车上
当时似乎是唯一之法，庭上
就是因为没有战争
所以也没有权利给你每次醉酒
就自己制造一场
现在我是看在你在军中的
辉煌记录
和你对本国安全所付出的贡献上
但这是你的最后机会
一百元罚款！
下一位！
你的警棍提出要跟你分开么，里兹？
你自以为是什么？在我车上洒尿
以为可以犯法，却无事般走开？
我们应被你的制服和勋章
吓得发抖？
你何不偶尔看看你的档案？英雄
看看日期，已是历史了
那个星期六晚上
你会躺在某暗巷中的血泊里
当你向上看时你会看见我在那里
等着瞧！继续作梦吧笨蛋！
要付出代价，我不给军人折扣优待
真不巧，你老婆给了
你总算出来了
那使你感觉很好，是不？
我们的山姆大叔很支持他的军人
毒死邻居的狗
你就是那种阴险的小人
看来你可以用得着一根好雪茄
它是最上等的货
只是他们不会太冒险
我们可以互相帮忙
在供给品方面，我有不少朋友
自然也知道谁不是朋友
所以我们可以互相帮忙？
是的，当然
若你的笔不尖，眼力差
我可以使你的军中生活很舒适的
更别提那些好处了
士官！你将那只雪茄拿开我面前
否则我将他塞过你屁股里
你想点都点不着
海威士官！
丹明少校要在他办公室见你
稍息！无事了，梅逊士官
是！少校
看在老天份上，海威！放轻松
- 别再一派陆战队的样子了
- 我就是，长官！
你手下有多少？大约24个，是吧？
还会有一些，长官！
有人到你的职级会想要退休
也许带着太太作环球航行
但那不是你的方法，对不对？
你选择离开我的单位
要求辞职至…陆战队第三单位
事实上，也是那一单位
你被踢出来
因为你的傲慢态度，作战不听令
那是事实，少校！
我和一些笨虫有点意见海威！
我真的不晓得该羡慕你
还是该反对你
反正，我想那也没什么区别
你离开此地，立刻！
去哪？长官！
第二排，陆战队第二师
你全知道的
遵命，长官！
枪炮士海威！
当心你所希望的，你可能会得到
下一个我们要请一位真正表演者
他是从新泽西来的
他是学生会的会长
是最佳的娱乐艺人
他来了！真正的摇滚乐巨星
先生女士们！迪克琼斯！
下来！废物！
老兄！你们老是向我眉目传情？
开玩笑！
你们何不放乖点！
身旁已坐着标准漂亮的美国人
好好看着那十加仑的袋子
你们看来像两巨人别动粗！
我会弹乡村音乐
再给我一次机会，是吗？
我们不喜欢黑人和你的音乐
别这样，老兄！再给我一次机会
我需要点钱！
如何？大约两站，是吗？狗屎
你想偷？不！老兄！我只是想坐
但那饮料占住了 !
你知道的
李和迪克，雷伦和表凯尼
甚至艾林菲力尔…
他们都办得到，我们也可以对否
我叫迪克琼斯，摇滚乐是生命
你知道，摇滚禾很能混的
但给人一个机会出来闯闯
见见一些人
并且有机会见见很体面的人
像你和我的那些歌迷们
我是歌星，老兄！你一定听过我
迪克琼斯是正点的
真正的摇滚乐歌手
闭上你的嘴，嬉皮！
你说我是嬉皮？老兄！
你不知道嬉皮流行有一世纪了
他们很能适应困苦时机的
我本会向你买一缶的
但我没有足够的铜板
通常我都靠唱歌换啤酒的
你可以免费来一缶
只求你少开口
谢谢你，老兄！
琼斯！
我叫汤姆海威，请你别口沫横飞
老兄！我能借一下你的杂志？
一定是某人留下来的
性，政治，生活主义
你的一大承诺
奇特岛，如何晒成古铜色
过着迷人的假期，请至牙买加！
不错嘛！老兄！
星期日和星期三的爱人作爱
老兄！这听来像首歌，听听看！
我在星期三遇见她，她是最好
那东西流进口中一定很过瘾的
星期日早晨我需要休息
因为她不刮胡，她不用剃刀
想用我的脸当脚踏车坐垫
天啊！我真鲜
喔！看这个妞儿
真可怕！她连浴巾都不要
你如果去那，是会冻死对不对？
她还不算差啊
我！我当然会听
但别想告诉我如何作爱
或是如何写音乐
因为我是这方面的青家
我是可比美那些巨星的
现在，我必须小睡片刻
如果你不介意我不再和你聊天
我需要睡眠
对！你知道那种事好玩
但你需要咖啡来提神
明白我的意思吗？
- 还要其它的？将军
- 不用了！
那些是什么勋章？
我不会说的！至少不会在白天说
那个女的真是疯狂
她不知道什么是12寸长又白的
没什么
是我自己编出来的笑话
如果那黑人不闭嘴…
我将告诉你，那黑人会流红血！
将会是美好的一天
告诉司机我马上出来
我用我的信用卡来请客
谢了！我来付小费好了
我伙伴要照顾他的宝贝
要我告诉你男厕里没有白天！
我来了，宝贝！时间宝贵
狗养的！
嘿！胯部腐烂！
那令我感到很困扰，离开我杯子
是！我想我应该早就被射杀的
如果你的脑子有你的舌头灵活
你早就是将军了
如果我有你一半丑陋的话，士官
我就会是个张贴广告明星了
仍然是个又狠又坏的畜牲
天！真高兴见到你
汤姆！回老家了！
别太兴奋，哈威！
人家会以为我是大人物
立正！早安，长官！
士官长！咖啡吗？长官！
不要
枪炮军士汤姆海斯向你报到，长官
那位作战行动长官
是难得开金口的古板的？
他看不起被宠坏的男孩
- 我要几时才有机会？
- 永远没有
士官长！长官！带海威士官进来
已有很长的时间了
我参加不少战役
韩战，65年南美战争，越战
历史上从没人得过这么多勋章的
我知道你的作战记录
也是你从供应部来这里的理由
我会很感激他来加入我们
安静
我想那些记最不是在夸大其词
但我不希望它继续下去
长官
我要这个营是最好的一旅
不指望非委任官的人带领他们
公众吵架，违反上级命令
目无法纪
不是我所想的标准军人
那是很小的过失，长官！
但已成为你的习惯了
一年前，你打了一位长官
你也知道后果如何
你想跟我试那个的话，海威士官
我会整死你的
你听清楚了没？陆战员
是，长官！
我不知道你在那一师里
有何人当你靠山
但我告诉你，我不喜欢
这是新的陆战队，新品种！
你这种人已经过时了
应该被封锁起来
只有战事爆发时才需要你
别老想你的过去
以为可以随心所欲，懂吗？
我知道若我不尽责的话
会有不少尸体的，长官！
少校！上面派枪炮士海威带第二排
是的，雷康
他们的前一位士官是个老战士
但他无法胜任
退休时什么都没有
如果你想要有个辉煌的退休的话
最好是照军方法纪来办事好吗？
最好不过了，少校！
我要求陆战员
上面却给我送来一个老人
那个侦察排，不是很热诚的一群
我要那些人振作起来
我要使那些人成为陆战员
解散！
他一向如此？还是想给人深印象
他是真正的军人，有板有眼
毫不苟且
的的确确是个守秩序的军人
露茵在家，她等不及要见你了
晚点我们去老酒吧，好好叙一叙
我想去，但我想最好先安顿一下
当然！我了解
抱歉，长官！
我是指，长官！士官长！
长官！这位是汤姆海威士官
他被派来训练雷康排
太好了！欢迎加入
我最好快走
我参加初级班的课已经迟了！
她妈妈知道他参加陆战队员吗？
还有，他是雷恩中尉
你们的排长多谢了 !
你不会想我们将新人交给生手吧
要不要我介绍你认识你的队员？
不！我自己会处理
用我的卡车，谢了！在那儿？
你只要看那个上有
梅锦士官长的就是
这是侦察排？
没有说英文的你呢？
没有如此幸运
我是枪炮军士海威
我管过不少军营
见过不少血，踢过不少床
杀过的敌人比你们加起来还多
鲍尔少校派我来负责这个雷康
我们自己照顾自己
你们可以照顾梦遗，主爱你们！
我知道这点
你们一点也不令我谁忘
雷康排的人踢人屁股
现在如此想稍微晚了点
因为你们上一任士官是个弱夫
你们当娃娃兵的日子已经过去了
现在可以开始举止像个陆战员了
谁请你来的？
我如此做并非想和你们一起洗澡
我不想在一个遥远的国土被射杀
因为你们是群庸才，懂了吗？
我在这里很有前途的
- 是，长官！
- 你呢？   - 是！
好呀
我是来此告诉你们
你们的生活已经结束了
你们不妨今晚进城狂欢一下
好好地和你们的甜心作爱吧！
无论如何，要发泄掉！
因为明天早上零六百小时
你们就得听我的了
你的床位在哪？
嘿！老兄！
到底怎么回事？
放我走！老兄！
真的，下辈子会做鬼来抓你
拿出来！你说什么？老兄！
你拿走我买车票的钱
也不需要用暴力呀！
我是很讲道理的
我是和平爱好者，真的
我只不过是开玩笑而已
我不过是稍微拮据一点而已
这儿！我有点钱
我只有这些钱了
还有吃饭的钱？
我真的只有这些了
还有小费
不！那是真的，真的，你欠我的
现在！是你的话和我的对质
所以是明早零600小时
也就是早上六点
大家都到外面集合！
那杂种！他刚刚拉伤了我的耳朵
他好运！在我揍他之前离开这儿
他妈的大猩猩
一定得想法子对这可恶的海威
对！但我们要怎么做？
我们等史威克出来
正是，史威！老兄
我们好好整整他，把头发拉下来
对，他会吃的
史威对付海威史威！
嘿！宝贝！
嗯，我打电话给她的太太…
你在回忙往日的日子？
该死！也不事先写信或打电话？
我不想打找你的睡眠
我替你拿瓶酒，棒极了，我正想
你的气色不错！
她们不能跟你相比较，甜心
她们可以的
若你想要很多女人
你就可以得到很多女士
不，不是那些小孩子
婚姻对陆战部队而言似乎不合适
结婚是我一生中最快乐的时光
若我还年轻
我会让你收回那句话
并扭转你的脚趾
我相信你会
艾姬总是会让你微笑的
那是很痛苦的
汤姆，她仍在城内
嗯！我想像的到
若她想寻找更多的赡养费
那她可就烦麻
因为我已近破产，不能让她
花一季的时间游览世界
她在那地方调鸡尾酒
我想她现在已嫁给了一位将军
嗯…我能回我的旧屋吗？
当然，你再去看她吗？
不，我能记这帐吗？
不
固执的女人，固执的女人
现在，从各地演唱成功
伯爵的恐惧
贵族的冷酷
超级摇滚乐巨星
史特约翰
好了，什么…
安蒂
你要点什么？啤酒 !
- 你来这里做什么？
- 就职
你还记得这白兰地
坏威士忌，性，人，我从未忘过
我们结婚时你不会说的如此刻薄
一直，只有你不会听过
看，汤姆，我正在工作
你看起来真捧！这灯光很暗！
真的，我看你走来走去
哦！拜托！别再戏谑了吧
太迟了，我已厌倦
你为什么来这里？
我来此想言归于好
你只是来此漫游，喝酒，不是吗
我不是来争吵的
如此的老狗在学习新的把戏？
我来此喝酒的
然而你一直在戏弄我
安蒂，这里有烦麻吗？
不，事实上
我很高兴你能与我的性友见面
这是汤姆海威
罗・杰尼，这地方是他的
听过你所有的传闻…
和你英雄的事迹
汤姆正好要走
安蒂，关店后我带你回家
与往日一样
让我听你们说这句话！
你可以迭择更好的
看看谁在谈话呀！
现在我要演唱另一首歌
是这地方所需要的
我要你们一起来摇滚乐
老兄！为何不理理你的头发？
纸老虎！
你真丑恶，兄弟
你应该去马桶里冲一冲！
你觉得很好笑？
你可以吊着你的二郎脚
捏住你的鼻子，放个屁
我打赌一定可以洗清你的心灵
别动，这里不允许暴力的
你们可以把那边漂亮的妞
喝着闻名的美酒，好吗？
好的
坐下
可以了吧！他们也没伤到任何人
滚远站！
这不关你的事
你嘴巴欠揍？
我只是要唱…
你要放了这些粗鲁的陆战员吗？
算了，这不关你的事
已把我搞火了，我要他们滚蛋
真的？
何不整理你的桌子
硬要我使你难堪呢？
你什么意思？
这是你的说服力，你说过的
我会送你回家
载着一只满脸伤痕邻居的小猫
什么样的角色如此说？
你没有权力这么做
他跟你开玩笑的
他在扯你的后腿
那些家伙并没有恶意
谁敢在你的地盆操你呢？
我是指欢迎来到流行舞会
你们都下地狱去！
你给我出去，约翰滚蛋
你给我小心点，可笑的人
别敲了我说别敲了，天杀的
你赴快离开此地！
我不要在此再见到你
我的酒还没喝完！
- 调鸡尾酒？
- 不，跟雷在一起
我太高估我离婚妻子的眼光
他比你还要上进！
该死！我真不敢相信
我真想踢杰尼的屁股
若不是要保护你的话
你欠我一次人情
我救了你一命
没什么意思，然而我们交换立场
去你妈的蛋！
大家别再作梦了
好了，起床！起来！
5分钟后外面集合
天！还不到五点，你说六点的
我不会看时间，我说慌
也许那共军会用新武器射中你
你们快点动，快起来！
你们是陆战队员，要随机应变
剩四分钟
只有一分钟梳洗
一分的时间包括刮胡子
用掉更多时间就太享受了
那不是我们的目的
睡得好？琼斯先生
这是恶梦，真他妈的恶梦
唤醒我，妈妈！求求你
上士！所有人员都到了
回去归队！
陆战队有几位好战士
不幸的是你们都不是
我要开出一条战线让其他人跟随
投降不是我们的信条
让我听你们说这句话！
投降不是我们的信条！
大声点！下回你们休假时
你们会领你们的退休金
投降不是我们的信条
再大声点！投降不是我们的信条
好极了！
脱掉T恤！什么？
我们都穿同样的T恤！
否则就不穿
- 你叫什么？
- 兰斯佛杰迪下士
你不该丢垃圾的，佛杰迪
那是不好的行为
- 你叫什么？ - 法戴
- 你呢？
- 波怀尔
- 你呢？ - 吉尤奈
- 你？
- 卡林斯
好吧！克莱德斯，卡莱迪克
艾杰克斯…
你们都很俊
你们看来都像模特儿
事实上！我要你们明天早上
头发又高又整齐，是每个人！
当你们看来像陆战队时
你们就会觉得像陆战队了
很快的，你们会像个陆战队
向右转！齐步走！左右左右左右
对！你是个傲慢自以为是的人
你说的好极了，没错！
卡帕纳斯，给我们口号
你的女友会哭泣的
现在给我一些口号！
我不记得了，上士！
最好快想，否则我们就一直操练
直到午夜
快做！老兄，做任何你想得到的
快做！卡帕纳斯，快做呀！
老兄，这个混蛋怎么啦，输了吗？
他要入侵南卡罗莱纳吗？
兄弟们，我们超过他，上！
王八蛋
他哪来这么好精力？
中尉！
哦！上士，早安！
你和侦察排是否已经见过了
我和我的人已经见过了
哦！好极了！
我要自由活动一阵子
好评估他们的实力
训练表上没有特定的任务
你要不要我来加入你们？
我相信在此有更重要的事，长官
其实！我在准备正式的战略文件
为了下星期的演习会
真的是很吸引人的工作
我不知道少校有没有告诉过你
我在大学时是ROTC
特种任务友队的指择官
我知道这点会睡的好些了
谢谢你，你上那所大学？
断肠脊！
断肠脊？没听过那学校呀！
很好！看来很好，真的很好！
对了，很光滑！
这儿闻起来像班葵工厂
脱掉那些T恤
上士！我们都是相同的了
要和我相同！
我们怎么知道你要穿什么颜色？
随机应变！你们很快就会适应的
快脱掉那些T恤！
整排向左转！齐步走！
你最好考虑一下
你在泰勒前可以你心
但这人是个狂人，他会逮到你的
你只管担心你自己吧！
老兄！祝你好运！
灯头泡一定是色盲
还有人有更好的主意吗？
庞帝他人呢？
他人不舒服，看来像鬼似的
他去检查身体了对吧？
是的，上士
我要营房今天大扫除
算了吧！上士
没多久之前，我们才清理过了
对呀！上士，好像是星期六吧！
真的？我们来投票决定
有多少人觉得营房如此就可以？
赞成！
好极了！好一个民主政策
我们就跑步吧！
立正！向右转！齐步走！
到底怎么回事？老兄
这是AK47型来福枪
是你们敌人所用的武器
当它向你们射击时
会有很明显的声音，记住！
我们走吧！
真是狗屎！老兄
他故意整我们，对我们开枪
我会被整死的
看看他，他的眼睛总是斜视着
真正邪恶的
我真想打烂他头
杀杀他的马威
不要这么做，他只是个低能儿
没错，拥抱着我
只是我遗失了我的宝贝
因为我们是侦察排
海威！我听说你回来了
威斯德
这些低能儿，根本保护不了自己
所以是你一直躲起来的目的
我和鲍尔少校在训练一连
作战的士兵
你能的唯一件事！威斯德！
就是生痔疮！
什么？
当你在浪费你的子弹时，贝杰迪
那些故人会使你成为瑞士芝士的
你射慢一点！
不是我错！老兄！
他妈的这武器出故障了
这来福枪没毛病，你靠紧一点！
你今早起来头上就着它了
不！我是为了你才戴这个的
真的？
是的，这种头盔很特别的！
经过不少的战役
对一位快要退休的人而言
是种敬意的表示
我真感动！
对！是我们说欢迎及再见的方式
还有，你遗失的那顶头盔
不会碰巧在当铺中吧！
上士！那是很严重的指控
我们对这些坏男孩有责任的
没错！你是的
我要在7点时看见你头上戴帽子
否则你会有大麻烦的
是！海威上士！
上士！我的枪卡住了
笨蛋
鲍尔少校要你严加督促你的人
如果鲍尔突然停住的话
你的脸会刚好在他屁股上
考帕他绝撑不到回营房去的了
海威是冷血的人
别让那混蛋你心你可以做到的
侦察
你对他说什么？士官
我说别给那混蛋满足感，长官！
在通讯和解放之间的字是…
- 我送你回去
- 当然，何不？
快！谁去看看他今天穿什T恤
老兄，那没多大关系的
因为他还是会有别的埋怨的
在科学怪人来之前生活容易多了
对，老兄！
我怎能在美国舞台表演呢？
美国士兵的玩意对我的手不好
各位！解散！
我说解散，现在！
我们那儿也不去
这些玩战争游戏的事
根本就是鬼扯
那是注意你的行为的问题
我们已经不在意了
因为我们已经不重要了
你已经被我们投票退出这一排了
迪克琼斯！你到外面去
否则我会踢死你
不！我不以为，宝贝，史威
史威！史威！
上士！我要你见见我的大朋友
史威乔汉森
史威！对这个人说几句好话
我要折断你的头！扭你的颈子
你瞧！自大的海威
我们已经不再需要你了
滚吧！笨蛋！别再回来
别再！别再！别再…
抬起你的下巴！
高一点！
现在马上出去集合！立刻！
我待会儿回来看你！史威！
我在外面等你处置！
不！乔汉森
你现在要成为陆战队员了
出去！是，长官
早安！弟兄们！我带你们去演习
但我不到海威上士！
不知道他上哪了
我的天啊！是谁？
长官！那是AK47型武器
我们的敌人所使用的武器
当它向你发射时
会有很大的声音，长官！
它是的，不是吗？
等等，佩姬！我送你回去
不！你先走，我有点痛
哦！知道了，今晚你休息
沟通的整个意义…管他的！
我真高兴某些事都没改变
你仍然知道女人想听些什么
我碰巧在这附近
也许你想坐下来谈谈
- 你在看女人的杂志？
- 什么杂志？
那些杂志啊！
对的，一定是有人留在车里的
- 谁？
- 邱卓
你甚至不知道他不会看这神令
别这样固执
你何不坐下我们可谈谈
我不是你的手下，随你命令的
跟我结婚如此糟？是的
全排立正！敬礼 !
谢谢你，上士！
多么好的早晨作军事演习
弟兄们！我们今天的演习
是要突击优越作战部队
利用掩护，供给，火力
和美国陆战队的积极天性
应该说是稍微极的陆战队员
我们要供应鲍尔少校的部队
及他的攻击目标
好增强他们的优越技巧
这武装每一部队都要戴着
它一接触到雷射光
就会发出哔哔的声音
你就晓得队上那个人员死亡？
抱歉中尉！你是否暗示不反击？
是的上士！少校想利用侦察排
来作训练的工具
那么如果这些人得参加作战
那时怎么办？他们只有送死的份
是的！我明白你的意思
你能和鲍尔少校谈谈吗？
出发吧！上士！
你跟不跟我们走？中尉
不！上士！我11点和医生有约
希望不会严重的使你
无法参加下一个战争
全排向右转！枪上肩！齐步走！
你肯定海威的人全都在埋伏区？
我知道的是，他们不会攻击我们
我很怀疑！
陆战队！今天要让侦察员好看！
全排立正！向右转，齐步走！
天啊！我刚加入时
以为会从飞机上跳伞下来
和敌人作战之英…
老兄！这是新式的陆战队
我们只是玩玩呀！
我们作战的唯一敌人是自己队员
你听见那声音在你呼我是好莱坞
我要平步青云到最上端
我会有我想要的各种女孩
少在那儿乱晃来福！
你制造太多声音了
有何关系！我们本来就不该赢的
你看太多电影了
狗屎！那是什么
笨蛋陆战队！那线本该是陷阱的
它可以炸掉你的腿的
你应该先派人查探的
你的后援呢？波怀尔！
你在后面有何用？
没有掩护火力我早就完了
当你们在此穷磨姑时
我们整排人都要送死了
嘿！少紧张！老兄！
那是我们来此的目的呀！
你说什么？我们来此的目的
我们突击鲍尔三次
我们在此，我们知道任务
笨蛋！谁说我们要在此突击鲍尔
你没听见雷恩中尉的话？
鲍尔少校要我们死
他好测脸他们的实力
我才不在乎鲍尔少校
我的职责就是使你们活命
我们向前走！
我们马上就到埋伏区了
我们知道
只是不知道你几何会遭攻击
长官
别慌！让他们再向前几码
我们就发射
他们来了，现在开枪！现在！
这不是埋伏计划，停火！
这不是埋伏区！
侦察！侦察！
- 士官长！
- 是！
将这该死的东西关掉
它的声音吵死人了，是不？
这个人超越职权！
轻视程序和不理睬我的指示
有一星期了，为什么？中尉
长官！我将训练表…
你想得太多，实际行动少了
你应该是个军官的
去看一下你的排手册！
是谁准许你改变训练表的？
我需要评估我的人！长官！
他们不是你的人！
你这个傲慢自以为是的杂种！
他们是美国陆战队的人
第二师的人
换言之，是陆战队第八团的人
也就是我的人，你也是！懂吗？
我唯一懂的是
如果我带一排无知的陆战队
进入作战区的话，我会送命的！
你要照我的计划行事，不准发问
我们明天要去作战的话
你的计划会害死这些人的
是你自作主张，是不是？
如果我不知那儿故障
我要如何修理呢？
你说的倒轻松！
长官！我给上士准许自由活动
我是指…那些人，长官
- 到外面去等！
- 遵命！长官
我要弄走你，海威
你知道什么好笑？
你要承担一切工作
迟早你会违反命令
老毛病又复发的
只是不断地发生，你无法自制
你太老，太笨了
太多自尊不能改变
我会乐意看你倒下去的
现在出去！叫那个白痴雷恩进来
他要见你，中尉！
抱歉！没那必要，中尉！侦察
你会让任何人来这里，是不？
这房里有个人可以解除你的痛苦
想喝醉，对着月亮狂哮
我们回到下层，没有阶级之分
别管P.F.C.好吗？
- 我是你们的人
- 我们是什么？邱卓
我们是清除瘤肉
为灯油而流血短发的好男儿
说的没错，我们一直是这样
我们是O－1－1
再说一遍
鲍尔上校
在一个暗且多云的早晨对我说
士官长，你是0－1－1
没有胜利…
一次和…韩战
一次败…越战
战争是败了，但我们胜了战役
下一次我不会败了
因为我的人已准备好了
你将要怎么做？
使他们成为陆战队员
史东尼杰克森
最好一排的中士
两个自卑自泣的糟老头
年轻军官乳臭未干想去打仗
你们的公司命名的
你们的军队全面警戒
上帝保佑
我找不到我的帐篷
我的被服？
该死！谁拿了我的雨衣？
老兄！别这么慌！
我们一定有时间作AWOL
各位！我们来检查一下装备
武器！现在维持简便
你们有靴子，用来打仗时走路
我们走！
帕吉他人呢？
他病了！一定是这些训练
我自己也不太舒服
你有过更糟的
那是当我酒醉时，你知道的！
快走！
DV1348申请表格
没有正确填写
我要你派一位较有效率的人办事
是，长官！
我要你确定每一轮的子弹都要数
全照数退回
我会确定不出差错的
懒散，贪婪和高效率！
你的那一排刚好可以整肃，上士
长官！我要提出
我们的队员能有些夜间眼镜？
那不是你的职责所在
我在想或许会…
填写一份正确表格寄给有关单位
申请表格？
敬礼 !
稍息！各位！
表示坎鲍尔少校！长官！
第71期
你的人情况如何？少校
我的人备战至死以保护我们国家
希望没有那个必要
我们是否会一起服役？
我不知道，长官！
邱卓士官长和我…
于67、68年时在第二营
我在70年时有一连来福队
那我们是会一起服过役了，长官
那是一定的
你对这个警报有何意见？
真他妈的鬼扯蛋！
再说一遍！
陆战队员是战斗员
不应该坐着感到抱歉
因他没有申请一些装备
似乎是值得观察的事，上士！
请继续！少校！
请注意！请注意！要去战争了
这是紧急的战斗队形
准备进行演习
我们退出了，警报已经取消了
可恶！
也许会有下次，长官！
帕吉？
哦！他呀
他人在哪？
嘿！老兄，你怎么了？
没人可以瞒得了我
如果你没有官阶的话
我一定踢你屁股的
但是因为我不使用暴力的
否则我一定叫你好看
我会给你折扣的
除此之外，帕吉是谁？
他不重要
他不是我兄弟
海威？
不错，我是海威
进来吧！找你的，帕吉
抱歉，我得告诉他
这是我太太莎拉
瞧！我表格全填好了
队上的收入是不够我们家用的
所以我找了份工作
你要退出海军陆战队？
不，不要
我们必须剪除所有BS繁文褥节
敲掉它，是不？
这有一项特别的发现
只有中士才有
别担心，你可以还的
来，你来抱他
谢谢你，谢谢你
你笑代表什么？
我一向认为你是圣诞老人
像那样拉另一个来玩
只有一件事可以使你进牢房
就是野战用的小型头灯
是的，长官，中士海威长官
嘿！你…你不能留下我一个人
这个人真没同情心
那么……
在帕拉桑的芙琳说你今晚休息
芙琳太多嘴了
我能清你喝啤酒吗？
当然！
经过这些年后
没有一点警告就再闯入我的生命
到我工作的地方去打找我
我几乎失掉我仅能找的唯一工作
然后你来这儿
指望我只是邀请你进来坐坐
你总是如此，海威！
你只有胆识，没有脑子
听来好像你在怕我？
是的！我怕我会再度困在这厨房
也不会是首次，是不是？
不是！
你的地方很不错！
谢了！你要杯子？
你仍然去上夜校
我每周工作5个晚上
我已不再年轻了！
散那些老时光！
只要你不提好时光就好
我们也会享受过，不是吗？
我不知道，我想不起那么久的事
你感觉如何？很好！
没有比现在更好的了
所以，是什么使你来这儿的？
我又回去侦察部队了
回去属于我的地方
- 如何？
- 这回不同了
又如何？
我已经来到尽头了
我不知道今后该何去何从？
我只想结束它，和我开始时一样
你想来点薯片或是盆圈饼？
好的，谢谢
额外津贴管用
告诉我一些事！
我们是否有在互相沟通？
我不懂！
在我们的关系里
我们有没有作有意义的沟通？
关系？
天啊！我以为我们结婚了
我最近一直在想过去
我只是在想哪儿出了差错？
- 是什么？
- 我，我们之间
这真像你，你似乎无法看清
无法一切都很顺利的
那么还有什么？
那不是很简单的
我经过我们刚结婚时所租的房间
真的好小！
时光过去，一切都会缩小的
告诉我！你对婚姻有何渴望？
我们会谈过鳄梨农场
买个后院能烧烤的房子
然后你志愿参加每一场战役
真该死！怎么了？
我怎么会如此愚笨？
你在说什么？
你这个畜牲！杂种！
你在我身上改变战略，对不对？
你究竟在说什么？
你放弃以往的刚烈个性
改用软的攻势
但我不要你我要你马上出去！
真是的，对一位成熟的女人而言
你的举止太不高贵了
你这该死的陆战队战争老马
我让你看看什么叫高贵
你滚蛋！快走！
滚蛋！马上滚蛋！别再回来！
拿走！死老头！
我再也不想见到你的脸
听到没？别再回来！
和以往一样疯狂，看在老天份上
狗屎！
谢谢你！
今晚的赢家是塞里达杜伟恩！
好个女孩，对不对？
嘿！慢着，不！不！你真是乱来
没有人喜欢输不起的家伙
竞争个屁！我们来投票好了！
人人都有权投票
大家投票给这大胸脯的说是
不，休想！
那么要投我票的人说摇滚屋！
摇滚屋！摇滚屋！…
你们到底想干什么？
这些监狱并没有多大的好处
别想跟我要签名
酷刑我，你可以使我挨饿
可以揍我！杀死我
只是别烦我！
很高兴能帮上忙，多谢了！
我的天啊！
鲍尔会想到这种情况的…
- 嘿！士官长
- 你是谁？
琼斯！第二营侦察排
天啊！海威那排人！过来帮一下
海威和我很熟，我们有如兄弟
我已付过他的保释金了
他需要你，佩姬！他需要战争！
我想我们受够了
哦！狗屎
咖啡
我一直就想来这个地方
看这些相片
老玛莉服务过三个战争的陆战队
他如何？
佩姬会使他再振的，她一向会的
谢了！夫人
海威真是不得了，高速度，沉着
当你在战场上，你不要其他人
断肠脊！那是事实
什么是断肠脊？
听着！我们必须先了解
然后才能…作更进一步
我们要作更进一步吗？
你如果想破镜重圆的话
但你却是战争第一，家庭第二
你永远如此的
我的前途里根本无法容纳陆战队
我不喜欢你说陆战队的口气
我可以用我喜欢的任何方式
来说陆战队
我有那权利的
没错！你是有
当他们送尸体回来时
我简直快疯掉了
铁棺材！我想我根本没有睡过
在68年
- 你记得那一年？
- 是，我记得
我早上起床，打开电视
我每晚在电视机前用餐
希望你会出现在新闻中
祈祷我不会
当我上床时，我在想
你在哪？在干什么？
你是否还活着？我根本无法得知
我想很多事对女人来讲很困难的
我发誓！我不知你的去处…
我很抱歉
没有关系！宝贝，没有关系！
没关系的
我们在沙漠里上上下下走
天天夜夜，然后…
激烈的战斗一场
死了不少人
我们是第23步兵队
不久之后，我们加入队伍的
那时我们比你年轻
我没有听过断肠脊
只是一场战争而已，令上没记载
它甚至没有地名，只有号玛
史东尼杰克逊
他是此战役的英雄
不少人死在这儿，真使我们心碎
谁是史东尼杰克逊？
老玛莉的先生，他是排队的士官
也是推荐海威得到荣誉奖章的人
海威上士他赢得CMH?
他利用两把机关枪进入这一区
三天没有合眼
后来他一个人夺下了那地方
当一切都结束后
我，史东尼杰逊和海威
我们是唯一活命的人
杰克逊后来？
他68年时在凯桑被杀
我能否为你们弄点吃的？
我可以很快弄好的
不用了，谢谢你，太太
失礼了！太太
你不会碰巧知道海威穿的颜色吧
先是咖啡，再来是深蓝
全排立正！向右转！齐步走！
各排要前进至指定区
这回是墨菲营区
不论谁先到达这儿
可以得到72小时的休假
长官！如你能加入我们
排队将会是无比的荣幸
多谢你，士官长
开始
乔汉森！快弄好肚带
长官！我有惧高症
- 我也是
- 你也是？
从飞机上跳出来
本来就不是一件自然的事
你只要做的正确就会没事的，来
我们走吧！
我们到了，我们是第一个到达的
哦！可恶！是第一排
- 少校！海威！
- 该死！
快走！各位我们给他们好看
第一排跟我走！
侦察排赢了!
上士！你不知道你的立场
第一排赢了！对！
我想我们已有赢家了，长官！
士官长，你是裁判
我命令你宣布第一排赢
长官，那不公平
那你打算要用何种方法下结论？
比赛！
好！兄弟，卸下装备
卸下装备，咱们上！
第一排赢！
我可不这么想，少校！
承认吧上士，第一排是本场之王
你是从何说起？
你的人使作我说是随机应变
他使作，他应付当时的情况
只有一个方法可以解决
排士官，下去一决高下
慢着！士官今天由我带这排队
老头！找个人取代你吧！
加油！少校！海威！海威！
真是太棒了！
击倒鲍尔少校和他的作战单位
我的手臂被他们的人咬了
看来你有不少肌肉了，波怀尔
我可能有沾到毒藤
它可能会传遍全身的
“我们不用再听他的鬼话了”
我觉得我愈来愈好了
哦！真不害羞！
先生女士！我告诉你们
海威上士是我最近见过
最令人心服的角色
没错！他使我们侦察的记录改写
海威是第一功臣！对！
我要为他编首歌好极了！
那是我们陆战队的灵魂！
他踢了很多驴子
在一个叫做断肠脊的地方
别再小看海威
他是个糟糕的精神之母
我告诉你们别的事
你们有谁知道海威会经因为
断肠脊一役而…得到最高荣誉
真不是盖的？
那是千真万确的事！
鲍尔少校要你们每位的声明
什么声明？
海威上士在训练时
未经准许而使用真实子弹
谁说的？
我以为你们大家都痛恨海威？
我听说他把你们都整得很惨！
你们不想再回复老样子？
没有人会管你们
在我看来
目前没有人会来管我们了
你们会有很好的周末
我先从你开始！
我没有什么可对你说的！
- 你？
- 我也是
你们真的不想要合作？
我们没什话跟你说的，威斯德
你何不回去你的那个第一排？
但这回可别气着离开！
只是离开，用脚尖走！
我恨社会场合！
总统要求开放营区
全部整齐军服
这太疯狂了！
我们会去的，汤姆海威士官
挺拔，威风，戴着你所有奖章
有很少人见过像你这样的英雄了
欢迎一位最高荣誉奖章的得主
是一件很荣幸的事
谢谢你，长官！
最近有没有碰见什么好俏妞？
不！最近没有
继续努力！
那种将军喜欢有功勋的士兵
你在派对中要如何表现？
弯起你的小手指
没有见过军人如此作过的
78年时JJ他是不是从派对中
偷偷溜出去？
不！那是我
JJ和我以及简宁想要比酒量
奇怪！我们来喝一杯
敬JJ和其它失去的东西
我所认识的人当中最好的
像这种派对
交谈的内容总是很乏味的
如果有后门，我想我要开溜了！
你知道这种场合的
如我介入你不会心碎吧！邱卓
我会没事的
我去看看有什么绝遇
你想跳舞？
你来此干嘛？
我刚好就在附近
有什么好笑？
这使我想起我毕业舞会时
你记得你和的舞伴之间
至少月8寸的距离？
我是记得！
是不是在第一晚我们就
是的，我是的
我必须说你是个疯狂的生物
你的杂志对那情形有何见解？
我不知道，我还没看那部份
你仍然在看它们？是的
它们对性有何看法？
不多，只说性很好的关系
你不必建立关系什么的
- 你真的想了解它是不？
- 我想是的
那是因为你快退休了
而你无处可去了，是不？
我不该如此说的，抱歉！
一点小事可能会使对方愤怒
我很抱歉！我不该那样说的
只是你我之间似乎无法和平相处
玩得开心？
我玩得很开心
- 很棒的聚会？
- 确实是的
我也在想我们谈过的鳄梨农场
汤姆！洛伊要我嫁给他
你怎么说？
请注意！
第二团陆战队及其它单位
刚刚接到警报通告
所有军官及士兵立即返回其单位
谢谢！
这又是另一个假警报，对不对？
我们要去作战了，弟兄们！
圣母！保佑，的确是作战！
我们要去格林纳达岛解放美国公民
- 什么岛？
- 格林纳达！是加勒比海岛
也是俗你的香料岛
离委内瑞拉东北海岸87哩
我们的任务是在西方岛上降落
侦察小组先替陆战队开路
我不能如此作，我忘了我的装备
好了！我们快走，快拿起来走吧
请注意！请注意！
在那里
到了！预备！
邱卓，你听到没？
邱卓！这是海威！你听到？
海威！我们要你们排队进入大学
你尽量少用军火，听到没？
结束后见！
散开！散开！
天啊！那是什么？
KC47有很明显的声音
你可肯定他们不太友善
你到角落上开始射击
掩护我！
他们一定是疯了，老兄！
快撒退！走吧！
他们撒退了，中尉！
好！你先去，慢慢地
敌方的侦察组！
最好快散开！
我相信他有伙伴在附近
快走！快点散开！走呀
好，走吧！
如我有机会回纽约
我会大吃一顿汉堡
你会不会开那堆土机？
在泽西时，琼斯是好手
快去！弗盖蒂你上去那机器上面
好7？我们走吧！
史威！用M60过去那儿
好极了！
我是摇滚宝贝
待在那，笨蛋！
蹲下！
主啊！请原凉我
来吧！我们走
进入前要让他们知道你的身份
那么就没有人会受伤
告诉他们我们是美国海军陆战队
美军队战队！
你射骷髅
该死！上士
美军陆战队！小姐
美军陆战队
你真该看看那浴巾后面的身材
嘿！他说要给我们冲浪板
到海滩去
我想我射杀他四次
是什么？波怀尔，是女的？
全部控制住了！没有伤亡
也没有敌逃
很好！我在离开前要拍些照片
我们在前来中途会碰见很强抵抗
可能是当地的军火
不！古巴的普通型及苏联来福枪
他们可能早就运送武器来此了
- 长官！命令
- 说吧！
别休息了！再回去作战
他们就在那山上
他们认为他们有我们的人
你为何不给好消息？
因为你太丑了
要每个侦察员上山去
等着狐狸连支援
保持联络！
那是命令，还是你的幽默？
出去！
你最好小心你的背
可能要穿蓝色的了
好！我们走吧！侦察组队员
快！接着走
你们小心！
快向前！不！卧倒！
像这样跑来这里是大错误的
带他们上来是我的错
现在说太晚了！
天啊！上士
考庞蒂！
无线电大队！
看我们能否有空中支援
没有用！无线电完蛋了！
别让他死，上士！
那也由不得我
好！快离开射区
你怎样？
我没事！我害了波怀尔
我还好！
- 其余的人？
- 都进来了
你在此掩护，你可以指望我
是我害死波怀尔的
现在怪自己也无补于事的
我可能会害死他们每个人的
但你没有呀！
只是别再犯同样错误，对不？好
我想我有办法打电话
呼叫空中突击队的
我想打紧急长途电话到
琼斯！你叫我？
是志愿工作，什么？
上去外面接通电话线
快呀！老兄，别老在那儿友呆
什么都指望琼斯
我的妈呀！这真是真正的战争
艾尔柯纳摇滚乐歌手不怕死
喂！喂！行了
一定行的，我差点为此送命
- 喂！接线生？
- 是的
这只是电话线被割断了
由那边付钱，什么？
有没有人有信用卡？
他们不接对方付费电话
别怕！迪克在！我离家绝不忘的
是的！6-6-0-5-5-8-0-7-1-1
布杨空军基地，你是真的？
红219! 632IK
- 再说一遍！
- 我不知道，电话断了
给我！
上士！你上哪？
如他们没看到信号麻烦就大了
但你不知道他们是否通过了
我们随机应变，长官！
狗屎！海威中枪了！
我们怎么办？长官！
我们走吧！
别死！
上士！
琼斯！我要你早上三点起来洗澡
听到没？
我真遗憾他没死
中尉！我们还在等什么？
好吧！魔鬼狗们，咱们进攻吧
冲呀
要他们出来，手举着出来
- 琼斯！过来
- 是，长官
带他们走
你们听见长官的话了
带他们走！走！走！.．・
你以为你在干什么？
只是享受一下景色，长官！
你违背我的命令
我说过保持联系
别狭自占领这个山坡
你起立！海威
不是不尊敬，长官！
你开始令我厌烦了
谁是负责军官？
我就是！麦尔坎鲍尔少校
是你带领此一攻击？
雷恩中尉及海威上士
他们违背我的命令，长官
我叫他们等待支援
但他们攻上山来了
为什么？
我们随机应变，看情势而进行
是我下令占领这山的，长官
雷恩！这将会毁了你的事业
你是否作战的生手？
是，长官！我是从供应部门来的
- 你对那行很精？
- 是，长官！
那么再回去那儿！
因为你不够格当指择官
这是陆战队及重任务单位，少校
我手下都是敢死队员
雷恩中尉及海威上士带一批新兵
首次出任务便大功告成
- 干得好！中尉
- 谢谢你，长官！
中尉！护送那些学生回去樱桃点
遵命！长官
你可以走了！
你们两个老油条还在此干啥？
快滚吧！
遵命！长官
邱卓！看来我们总算作对了
- 那是我家人！
- 哦，好极了！
你有家人来？
没有！但这是个美好日子
我要好好享受
给她们颜色，老兄！
对！给她们颜色瞧瞧
是的，我会的
今天是个美好日子
迪克琼斯打算好好享受
- 你明白我的意思？
- 随时！随时！
我想你可以如愿了
头发再留长，戴耳环！
成为摇滚乐混蛋
邱卓士官长给我最好的忠告
你相信？
他说我当陆战队员比当歌星合适
比我也是这么认为
- 你呢？
- 我受够了
这种生活我已厌倦了
况且，谁还要当英雄
迈克尔？
嘿，亲爱的！
你好吗？
这些东西对你来说是不是太老套了？
这是第一次
那是我的女士们来了！
再见！上士，我有任务了！
怎么样了？
- Here's that 410.
- Right, Moe. Thanks.
[PHONE RINGS]
MAN: I've been pumping pussy
since Christ was a corporal.
[TOILET FLUSHES]
I've gotta tell you, the best poontang
I ever paid for was in Da Nang.
The girls were checked out daily.
And we got laid in a safe, orderly,
proficient, military manner.
Until some suckhead
writes home to Mama...
...and says he dipped his wick
in the Republic of--
Well, then the shit hits the fan.
A committee of congressmen,
who, asshole to asshole...
...couldn't make a beer fart
in a whirlwind...
...starts telling your basic ass-in-the-grass
Marine, "No more short time."
We respond in true
Marine Corps fashion.
We salute and do an about-face...
...double-time back to
the boom-boom garbage dump...
...where we proceed to get
the clap, the drip, the crabs...
...and generally a poor attitude
towards the female of the species.
War is hell, boy. That's a fact.
I don't like soldier boys.
Say what?
You wanna pop that puppy's can, you
don't gotta grease him so hard, jarhead.
Sounds like you're a man
of experience.
What the fuck's that mean, grunt-shit?
It means be advised
that I'm mean, nasty and tired.
I eat concertina wire
and piss napalm.
I can put a round through
a flea's ass at 200 meters.
So you go hump somebody else's leg,
mutt-face, before I push yours in.
Ain't gonna be so smart with your
balls stuffed in your mouth, jarhead.
Oh, shit.
Hang on to this, boy.
I think war's just been declared.
[GRUNTING]
Why don't you just sit there and bleed
a while before you taste some real pain?
[PANTING]
Maybe first I carve me
some faggot wings.
He'll kill him.
[GRUNTING]
[MEN MURMURING]
[MEN CHUCKLING]
Then again, there was
this dusky gal in Bangkok.
A real crossway breezer, I swear.
JUDGE: Thank you for your testimony,
Officer Reese.
Sergeant Highway.
Drunk and disorderly.
Fighting in a public establishment.
Urinating on a police vehicle.
Well, it seemed like the thing to do, sir.
[LIGHT CHUCKLING]
Just because there's no war going on...
...doesn't give you the right to start one
every time you get drunk.
I'm taking into account
your excellent military record...
...and your commitment
to the security of this great nation.
But this is your last chance.
One-hundred-dollar fine. Next.
[BANGS GAVEL]
Your nightstick file for divorce, Reese?
Who do you think you are,
pissing on my squad car?
Think you can break our rules
and just walk away?
We're supposed to wet our pants over
your dress blues and colored ribbons?
Read your file sometime, hero.
Check the dates.
It's ancient history. One night,
you'll be puking blood in an alley.
You'll look up, see me.
Then we'll see.
- Keep dreaming.
- You'll pay full price.
- I don't give a serviceman's discount.
- Too bad. Your old lady does.
[AIRCRAFT APPROACHING]
Just about cleaned you out.
Makes you feel good, doesn't it,
helping Uncle Sam battle dirty drawers?
Just pump the dog again, Jake,
or are you always that slack-eyed?
Looks like you could use a lift.
Suck on this. Smooth as a prom
queen's thighs, only not so risky.
Havana cured.
Got a pal in Guantanamo in Supply.
We do each other favors. I got lots
of friends. I can always use another.
- So we can do each other favors?
- Yeah, sure.
If your pencil wasn't so sharp and your
eyesight not so clear around here....
I could make your lot in military life
a lot comfier...
...not to mention downright rewarding.
You get that contraband stogy
out of my face...
...before I shove it so far up your ass you'll
have to set fire to your nose to light it.
Gunny Highway. Major Devin
wants to see you ASAP.
- At ease. That will be all, sergeant major.
- Aye, aye, sir.
For chrissakes, Highway, relax.
Stop being so gung ho.
That's what I am, sir.
What do you got now, about 24,
don't you?
And then some, sir.
Some men in your position
would look forward to retirement.
Maybe take the wives on
a round-the-world cruise.
But that's not your way, is it?
You choose to harangue my staff
with a request for transfer to a...
...Fleet Marine Force unit.
The very unit you got busted out of
some time ago...
...for insubordination.
Conduct unbecoming.
That's true. I have had my differences
with some limp dicks.
Highway!
I truly don't know whether to admire you
or resent the living hell out of you.
Either way, it doesn't matter.
You're out of here immediately.
What did I do?
Second Recon Battalion.
Second Marine Division.
You're going home.
Aye, aye, sir.
Gunny Highway.
Sir?
Be careful what you wish for.
You might just get it.
LEADER:
Whoa! Hut!
[LEADER GIVING INDISTINCT ORDERS]
["TAPS" PLAYS OVER SPEAKERS]
MAN: We're gonna bring up the last victim.
A true-blood, born in Jersey.
He's the president of punk,
the earl of funk.
Here he is, the next king of rock 'n' roll,
ladies and gentlemen, Stitch Jones!
BOTH:
Stitch Jones?
[PLAYING ROCK MUSIC]
[SHOUTING]
Whoa, whoa.
Do I mess with y'all all when
you play "Romance the Sheep"?
Bag these geeks.
Keep America beautiful.
- Put a 10-gallon bag over their head.
- Let's take care of this.
You look like the twin towers
gone cellulite. Heh-heh-heh.
[MIC FEEDBACKS]
I can play country western.
Give me a chance.
I know Merle Haggard,
the Beverly Hillbillies.
Come on, man. I need the money!
- How far?
- About two stops.
Shit.
You the maid?
I want the seat, but the shit
ain't worth dying over.
Hell. You know.
Liz and Dick. Lennon and McCartney,
even. Ali and Frazier.
They worked it out. So can we.
Stitch Jones is the name.
Rocking and rapping is the game.
Pleased to meet you too.
Banged up my Corvette. But I figure
it's a chance to meet regular people...
...dudes like yourself.
People like my fans.
I'm a singer. Stitch Jones.
Earl of funk. Duke of cool.
- Ayatollah of rock 'n' roll-ah.
- Shut your face, hippie.
You say "hippie," man?
Ain't been no hippies for centuries.
You been freeze-dried or doing time?
Whew.
One of those would sure go down nice.
I'd buy one from you, but I don't
have my plastic. Usually my lackeys--
You can have one, if it shuts
the hole under your nose.
Ah. Thank you, my friend.
Jones.
This doesn't mean you can
blow in my ear. Tom Highway.
Yo, man, these ain't your magazines.
Somebody must have left them there.
"The Sexual Politics of Living Alone."
[CHUCKLES]
"The Big Commitment and You." Ah.
"Island Erotics: How to Stay Tan,
Tickly, and Tantalized...
...in the Cool Waters of Jamaica."
[IN JAMAICAN ACCENT]
Not bad, man.
[LAUGHS]
Ahh.
[SIGHS]
"Sunday Sex with a Wednesday Lover."
Yo, man, that sounds like a song.
Check it out.
I met her on a Wednesday
She was the best
Come Sunday morning
I needed rest
'Cause she didn't shave,
She didn't use Neet
Tried to use my face
As a bicycle seat
[LAUGHS]
Word! Am I fresh?
Ahh. Ugh.
This chick's got some angry titties.
Hostile projectiles.
- Put your shit in, you get frostbite.
- She isn't so bad.
You wanna talk, I'll listen,
but don't try to sell Stitch Jones...
...on making love or making music,
because I'm an authority. Born to screw...
...and bred to sing. That's me.
Now, I've gotta cut some Z's.
So if you don't mind, keep down
the chatter while I get my beauty sleep.
[SIGHS]
Groupies are fun, but you need
vitamin E. They wear you out.
- Anything else, general?
- No, I'm fine.
What are all those medals?
I'll never tell. At least
not while the sun's shining.
[LAUGHS]
This babe is wack.
She doesn't know what's
12 inches long and white.
Nothing!
[LAUGHS]
Hey, man, no offense.
Just working on my routine.
I'll tell you what's black and bleeding
if it don't shut its face.
Mellow, man. It's gonna be a nice day.
[HORN HONKS]
- Tell the driver I'll be right out.
- I'm gonna use my plastic. My treat.
Well, thanks. I'll get the tip.
Oh, uh....
My buddy's gonna take care of that.
He said to tell you:
"There's no sun shining
in the men's john."
I'm here, baby,
let's do some distance.
Son of a bitch.
Hey, crotch rot.
Gonna slurp my lifer's juice
out of my own cup?
Yeah, I guess I should have
gotten shots beforehand.
If your brain was as quick as your
mouth, you'd be a 20-star general.
If I was half as ugly as you,
I'd be a poster boy for a prophylactic.
Still a mean and nasty bastard.
Good to see you, Tom.
Back where you belong!
Take it easy. Everybody's
gonna think I'm spoken for.
Ten-hut.
Morning, sir.
Sergeant major.
Coffee, sir?
Negative.
Gunnery Sergeant Thomas Highway
reporting for duty, sir.
That operation officer's farthole is
sewed so tight he shits out of his mouth.
Academy?
Big-time football hero.
- When am I ever gonna get a break?
- Never.
POWERS: Sergeant major.
- Sir!
POWERS:
Bring in Gunnery Sergeant Highway.
Been in a long time.
I've felt a little heat, sir.
Korean. Dominican in '65.
Three tours in Nam.
Hell, he's carrying so much shrapnel,
he can't pass through a metal detector.
I haven't as yet
had the privilege of combat.
I came over from Supply and Logistics.
An unappreciated field of endeavor, sir.
Quite.
My record of achievement
thus far has been exemplary...
...and I fully intend for that to continue.
Sir.
I want this battalion
to be the class of the division.
I expect my non-commissioned officers
to lead by example.
Public fighting and insubordination to
civilian authority are not good standards.
- It was a minor altercation, sir.
- You make a habit of doing that.
A year ago you hit an officer.
I went to Annapolis with that man.
You try that with me and you'll drag your
butt in a sling for a month. You hear me?
Yes, sir.
I don't know what strings you pulled to get
back in this division, but I don't like it.
This is the new Marine Corps.
A new breed.
Characters like you are an anachronism.
You should be sealed in a case that reads,
"Break glass only in the event of war."
No tolerance for old-timers who think...
...you know better and can
have it your way. Understand?
I understand a lot of body bags
get filled if I don't do my job, sir.
CHOOZOO:
Major.
Division has assigned Highway
to our reconnaissance platoon.
Yes, recon.
My last sergeant was
an old-time combat vet too.
But he went R.O.A.D. on me.
Retired On Active Duty.
Had a few months to retirement,
figured he'd coast.
Allowed the men lapse into mediocrity.
You're close to mandatory retirement
yourself, aren't you?
That's right, major.
Well, I ask for Marines...
...the division sends me relics.
The men in Recon Platoon are less than
highly motivated, to say the least.
And I want those men in shape.
I'll make life-takers and
heartbreakers out of them, sir.
Dismissed.
Is he always like that or
just trying to make a good impression?
He consults his manual
before he mounts his old lady...
...to ensure he performs in an orderly--
BOTH:
Proficient military manner.
Chow with Helen and me tonight.
Later, we go stomp some brain cells
and tell some story.
- I'd like to, but I better get organized.
- Sure, I understand.
RING:
Oh. Excuse me, sir.
I mean, gunny. Sergeant major.
This is Gunnery Sergeant Highway.
He's been assigned to Recon Platoon.
Oh. Outstanding, welcome aboard.
Well, I gotta hightail it.
I'm late for pre-scuba school.
Lord.
His mama know he's playing Marine?
By the way, he's Lieutenant Ring,
your platoon leader.
Thanks a lot.
You didn't think you was just gonna tilt
nipple to a bunch of no-rank fuzzbutts?
- Want me to intro you to your troops?
- No, no, that's all right.
- Take my pickup.
- Hey, thanks. Where is it?
Just tell by the sign.
It says: "Sergeant major."
[ROCK MUSIC
PLAYS OVER SPEAKERS]
Is this Recon Platoon?
No speak English.
You?
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
[TURNS MUSIC OFF]
[TURNS MUSIC ON]
[MUSIC STOPS]
My name is Gunnery Sergeant Highway.
I've drunk more beer, pissed more blood,
banged more quiff, busted more...
...than all you numb-nuts put together.
- Major Powers has put me in charge.
- We take care of ourselves.
You couldn't take care of a wet dream.
- God loves you.
SOLDIER: I know that.
You men do not impress me!
Recon Platoon kicks butt.
- Ow.
- If you ladies think you can slip and slide...
...because your last sergeant was a pussy...
...who was just marking the days,
well, queer bait...
- ...start acting like Marines right now.
- Who invited you?
I'm not doing this because I wanna
take long showers with you assholes.
And I don't wanna get my head
shot off in some faraway land...
...because you don't habla.
Comprende?
Oorah!
- You?
- Yes, gunny.
[MAN HUMMING]
[SINGING]
I think you're fine
And you got that big behind
Well, well, well, well.
I'm here to tell you all
that life as you know it has ended.
You might as well all go to town tonight.
Laugh and make fools of yourself.
Rub your pathetic little peckers up against
your honey, or stick it in a knothole.
Whatever it is, get rid of it,
because at 0600 tomorrow...
...your ass is mine.
Where's your bunk?
Yo, man. Come on!
What the hell's going on?
[SOLDIERS CHATTERING]
Aah! Aah!
This is gonna mess up your karma, man.
It's gonna haunt you in your next life.
- Let's have it.
- What?
- The money from my ticket.
- No need to use violence, man.
I'm a peace lover. I was down
with the money on my luck.
Yeah. I got a little money right here.
- That's all I got.
- And the meal?
- Meal?
- Yeah, the meal.
All right.
- That's really all I got.
- And the tip.
- That's really it, man. Aah!
- You owe me.
[STITCH GROANS]
Now, it's my will against yours.
And you will lose.
So 0600 tomorrow.
That's 6:00 in the morning for
all you people who don't habla.
Damn! He just tore off my ear.
Lucky he had a chance to escape
before I kick his ass.
Big leatherneck,
jarhead motherfucker.
- Something's gonna have to be done.
- What are we gonna do?
- Wait till the Swede gets out of the brig.
- That's it. The Swede, man.
- He'll rip his head off and dump in it!
- Then eat it.
- I would've done that.
- Goodbye, Highway!
ALL:
Swede! Swede! Swede!
[ALL SHOUTING]
Hey, baby.
I called his wife--
You fool around on the first date?
Oh....
[LAUGHING]
Damn you, boy.
Don't you know how to write or call?
I didn't wanna cause you
any sleepless nights, thinking about me.
- I'll get you a beer.
- Great. I could use one.
That's for sure.
You look great.
They don't make them
like you anymore, sweetheart.
Oh, hell. Sure they do.
But if you want a lot from a woman,
you have to give a lot.
Not this kid. It seemed marriage and
the Marine Corps weren't too compatible.
Panther piss. The best years
of my life were with a Marine.
If I was a little younger, I'd make you
eat your words and curl your toes.
Yeah, I'll bet you could.
Aggie always kept a smile
on your face.
That was pain.
Tom, she's in town.
Hmm. Well, I figured as much.
If she's looking for more alimony,
I'm so broke I couldn't get out of sight...
...if it took a quarter
to go around the world.
She's cocktailing over at the Palace.
I figured she'd be married
to a general by now.
Uh....
Can I get my old room back?
- Hell, yes. Are you gonna see her?
- Hell, no. Can I run a tab?
Hell, no.
Tough woman.
[CHUCKLES]
[LOUD ROCK MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[CROWD SHOUTS]
[MAN LAUGHS]
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
EMCEE: And now, back from an awesomely
successful tour...
...the earl of funk,
the duke of cool...
...the ayatollah of rock 'n' roll-ah:
Stitch Jones!
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
[PLAYING ROCK MUSIC]
[SINGING]
Stop telling me what to do
And that goes for your mama too
Ask me and I'll tell the truth
He-hey
You need to call up Dr. Ruth
Girl, you know I love you
But I ain't stupid
Said you know I love you
Don't be illin'
I'm just chillin'
No need to make a killin'
A kiss is just as thrillin'
And I'm still willin'
So forget all about it
Baby, we can do without it
Yo, if you shout about it
Believe it, don't doubt it
Your daddy works at IBM, baby
So good for you
Good for them
Baby
Your brother says he's being nice
I don't need his free advice
Girl, you know I love you--
Okay, what will it--?
Aggie.
- What do you want?
- A beer.
- What are you doing here?
- Ordering.
STITCH: Shake it, don't break it
No need for you to fake it
I know we can make it
Girl, you know I'll turn you out
Make me scream
I need to shout
Kiss me
And you make my day
I love it when you talk that way
You even remembered the brand.
Bad whiskey, bad sex and bad men,
I never forget.
You didn't talk dirty like that
when we were married.
Heh. Always. Only you were never there
to hear it.
- Look, Tom, I'm working.
- Hey.
You look great.
- The lights are low.
- No, I mean it.
- I'd recognize you coming and going.
- Save the banter for your bimbos.
It's late, I'm tired, my feet hurt.
What are you doing here?
I'm back with recon.
And you just happened to wander
into the joint? Ain't life grand?
- I didn't come here to fight.
- You mean old dogs do learn new tricks?
I just come here for a beer,
and you're ragging my ass already.
Aggie, is there a problem here?
No, as a matter of fact, I'd like you
to meet one of my favorite exes.
This is Thomas Highway. This is
Roy Jennings, he owns the Palace now.
Heard all about you.
And your bullshit heroics.
Uh-- Uh-- Tom is just gonna leave. Heh.
Aggie, I'll take you home
after we close up...
...as usual.
You sure can pick them, I'll tell you.
Hah. Look who's talking.
Ah, you know I love you
Oh, please
And I ain't crazy neither, hah!
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
All right.
I'm gonna play something from N.Y.C.
I want all of you to rock the house!
Why don't you get your hair cut, huh?
[LAUGHING]
You're so ugly, you need to be out
at the airport sniffing luggage.
- You think you're funny?
- Tell you what:
Y'all, cross your legs,
hold your noses and fart.
- You could clear out your minds.
- Say what?
Yo, yo, yo! Tell you what.
Don't start no S-H,
won't be no I-T. We got ladies here.
Point yourselves this way, have a drink
with the nation's finest.
- All right.
- Chill out.
MEN:
Hoo! Hoo!
Knock it off! I said knock it off,
goddamn it!
Sit down, buddy!
- Why don't you lay off them?
- Why don't you stay out of this?
- It's none of your business.
- What are you, some kind of smart-mouth?
- I'm just trying to sing here.
- You get off on rousting Marines?
Leave it alone.
It doesn't concern you.
- I chew on jarheads and spit them out.
- You do?
Why don't I bend you over that table
then, and nail you in the keister?
- What are you talking about?
- That's what your persuasion is.
I'll send you home with an "I just pumped
the neighbor's cat" look on your face.
[CHUCKLING]
- What kind of faggot talk is that?
- You have no right to do this.
Roy, man.
He's just pulling your leg, man.
They don't mean nothing. Who'd have
the bad sense to fuck with Roy Jennings?
I mean, welcome to fantasy disco, huh?
The hell with both of you.
And you're out, Jones. Hit the road.
And you watch it, funny man.
Get your tight little butt out of here.
- I never want to see you in this place again.
- I left my beer.
- I have got a future here, damn it!
- Cocktailing?
No, with Roy.
Maybe I expect better
out of an ex-wife of mine.
He's an improvement over you!
I don't believe this shit, man!
I'd have kicked Roy's ass
if I wasn't protecting you.
Redneck people love me.
So you owe me one. I saved your life.
This doesn't mean we're gonna be
swapping spit in the shower.
Fuck this jarhead sucker.
HIGHWAY:
Drop your cocks and grab your socks.
Off your ass and on your feet.
Get up!
Knees to the breeze in five minutes.
- It's goddamn 5:00. You said 6:00.
- So I can't tell time. So I lied.
Maybe some communist's gonna make an
appointment to pop you a new asshole.
Let's go! Move out! You're Marines
now. You improvise. You adapt.
Four minutes. Fall out.
Shit.
We move swift. We move
silent. We move deadly.
Only one shake of those wangs.
Any more than that constitutes pleasure.
- Sleep well?
- Man, this is a nightmare!
Wake me up, Mama!
- Gunny, platoon's formed for PT.
- Take your post.
The Marines are looking
for a few good men.
Unfortunately you ain't it.
We will blaze a path into battle
for others to follow.
Surrender is not in our creed.
Let's hear you say that.
ALL [WEAKLY]:
Surrender is not in our creed.
Louder, or next time you get R and R,
you'll be collecting pensions.
ALL: Surrender is not in our creed.
- Louder!
ALL [LOUDLY:
Surrender is not in our creed!
Oorah.
- Strip off those T-shirts.
- What?
What's he talking about?
You'll all wear the same T-shirts
or none at all.
- Shit....
- He's crazy.
[YAWNS]
- What's your name, Marine?
- Lance Corporal Fragetti, gunny.
You shouldn't litter, Fag-etti.
It's ecologically unsound.
What's your name?
- Aponte.
- Yours?
- Profile.
- Quinones.
- Yours?
Collins.
All right, Colitis, Cojones...
...Prophylactic, Ajax.
You boys are handsome.
You ladies look like models.
I want your hair high and tight
tomorrow morning. Everybody.
When you start looking like Marines,
you'll feel like Marines...
...and pretty soon you'll act like
Marines. Right face! Forward march!
Left, your left, your left,
right, left....
LEADER:
Left, right, left, right, left....
When my boy Swede gets out of the brig,
this sucker's dead.
- You got that right, bro!
- Right on!
Ooh-oh-oh-oh!
ALL:
- Whoa-ho-ho.
LEADER: Turn right!
ALL [CHANTING]:
Mama, Mama, can't you see
LEADER:
What the Marine Corps has done to me
ALL:
LEADER:
Used to drive a Chevrolet
ALL:
LEADER:
Now I'm marching every day
HIGHWAY:
Cojones, give us a cadence.
Your girlfriend's gonna weep
when I bite that finger off.
- Give me a cadence now!
- I don't remember any.
Think fast or I'll run your ass
until midnight.
Do it, man! This dude is certifiable.
Model A Ford and a tank full of gas
ALL:
Handful of pussy and a mouthful of ass
GROUP:
Yo, man, what's this sucker, lost?
What's he gonna invade, South Carolina?
All right, men, let's smoke
this sucker's ass. Come on!
[ALL SHOUTING]
[ALL PANTING]
Asshole.
What did they put in his Geritol?
Lieutenant.
Oh. Gunny. Good morning.
Missed you and Recon Platoon at PT.
- The men and I were getting acquainted.
- Excellent.
I want to freelance them for a while.
To evaluate them.
There's nothing on the schedule.
You want me to join you?
You have important work here.
I am preparing a paper on tactics
and strategy for the War Club seminar.
Oh, it's fascinating stuff. Ow.
I don't know if the major told you...
...but I was commanding officer
of my ROTC detachment in college.
I'll sleep better at night
knowing that.
Thank you.
What college did you go to?
Heartbreak Ridge.
Heartbreak Ridge?
I've never heard of that school.
[SOLDIERS YELLING]
Shit!
[GRUNTS]
Oh, yeah, that looks nice. Real nice.
Oh, yeah.
Slick.
[SNIFFS]
Smells like a Ben Gay
factory around here.
Strip off those T-shirts.
- We're all the same.
- Same as me?
- How are we supposed to know--?
- You improvise, overcome, adapt.
Now, get off those goddamned
T-shirts now.
Platoon, right face.
Forward march!
You'd get away with that with Tyler.
But this cat, he's nuts. He'll catch you.
Don't worry yourself.
Hey, man, the few, the proud,
the chumps.
SOLDIER: Oh, no!
- Man, we can't win for losing.
He must have the key to the PX.
Anybody else got a better idea?
Where's Aponte?
He's sick, man. He looked like
living proof of life after death.
Went to get checked out.
- That's right, gunny.
- Yeah.
I want the barracks field-dayed
and squared away ASAP today.
We cleaned them just a while ago.
Yeah, gunny, you know, it's Saturday.
Well, let's have a show of hands.
How many people think the squad bay
is ready to go as is?
SOLDIERS: Yeah!
- There you have it. Democracy in action.
- All right.
- We'll run instead. Attention!
Right face!
Forward march!
Double time!
[SOLDIERS SHOUTING]
SOLDIER:
What the hell's going on, man?
This is the AK-47.
The preferred weapon of your enemy.
And it makes a distinctive sound
when fired. So remember it.
Let's move out.
Oh, man, that's bullshit, man.
He's shooting at us. What the fuck?
I don't need this, man.
That's wrong, man.
Yo, you all, check the way he's always
squinting his eyes.
Trying to talk all tough.
I should slap him myself
just to call his bluff.
[RAPPING] Don't do that, man
He's just a jarhead fool
You're right.
But hold me back
In case I lose my cool
Because we're the Recon Platoon
We always gung ho
Gung ho to party
- Or watch The Late Show
- Till Highway came along
His abuse we don't need
But we'll end this bullshit
ALL:
When Highway meets the Swede
[ALL CHEERING AND WHOOPING]
- He gonna kick his ass.
- Right!
[GUNSHOT]
- Highway, I heard you were back.
- Webster.
These retards couldn't fight their way
out of a shithouse.
Is that where you've been?
Me and Major Powers are building
an elite company of fighting men.
The only thing you could build
is a good case of hemorrhoids.
- What?
- You're blowing all your ammunition.
Mr. "I hate Americans" will make you
into Swiss cheese.
- Slow down your fire.
- It's not my fucking fault.
The fucking weapon
is fucking fucked up.
Nothing wrong with that rifle.
Keep it tight.
[GRUNTING]
Did you wake up
with a piss-pot on your head?
- No, gunny, I wore this in your honor.
- Is that so?
This is a classic piece of issue.
You know, sands of Iwo Jima, Khe Sanh.
All that old antique stuff.
A nice tribute to an aging veteran
as close to retirement as yourself.
I'm touched.
You know, a recon way of saying
welcome and, inevitably, goodbye.
And the Kevlar helmet you were issued?
That didn't by chance find its way
into a pawnshop in town, did it?
No way. That's a serious implication.
- We're responsible for these.
- That's right, you are.
So I want Kevlar on your head by 1900
or you won't have a head to wear it on.
Yes, sir, Gunny Highway,
sergeant, sir.
Gunny, my weapon's jammed.
[GUNSHOTS]
- What the--?
- Oh, shit!
[SOLDIERS GRUMBLING]
SOLDIER:
Asshole.
- What the--?
- You all right?
Major Powers is gonna teach you
how to discipline your men.
If Powers ever comes to a sudden halt,
your face is gonna go halfway up his ass.
Profile won't make it back
to the barracks.
Powers is cold-blooded, man.
HIGHWAY:
Left...
...right...
...left.
[PANTING]
[QUIETLY]
Come on, Profile.
Don't give the prick the satisfaction.
You can make it.
Recon!
What did you say, gunner sergeant?
I said, "Don't give the prick
the satisfaction," sir.
"Sensitive dialogue during
communication of the relationship--"
[DOOR OPENS]
- Follow you home?
- Sure, why not?
[STARTS ENGINE]
Come on, guys.
Somebody see what shirt he's wearing.
It don't matter, he'll find something
to complain about anyway.
Life was a hell of a lot easier
before Frankenstein paid a visit.
STITCH:
How am I gonna play American Bandstand?
This macho shit is bad for my hands.
People, fall out.
I said fall out. Now!
We ain't going no place.
- All this play-war stuff is bullshit!
SOLDIER: Yeah.
Gunny, this is all a question
of mind over matter.
We no longer mind
because you don't matter.
[SOLDIERS LAUGHING]
You've been voted out of office, baby.
Mr. Jones...
...you fall out on that street or
I'm gonna kick your ass off this planet.
Oh, I don't think so, babe. Swede?
SOLDIERS:
Swede, Swede, Swede....
[ALL CONTINUE CHANTING "SWEDE"]
Ah. Gunny, I'd like you to meet
my big friend, Swede Johanson.
Swede, say something charming
to the man.
I'm gonna rip your head off
and shit down your neck.
[SOLDIERS LAUGHING]
See, Grungy Highway, we ain't got
no use for you no more.
Hit the road, Jack.
[SINGING]
And don't you come back
ALL:
No more, no more, no more
[GRUNTING]
[SOLDIERS SHOUTING]
Stick your chin up, man.
Higher.
SOLDIER 1: Christ.
SOLDIER 2: Goddamn.
[GROANING]
Now, get your ass out on that street,
ladies, right this second!
I'll check you later, Swede. Yeah.
Sir, I'll wait outside for the MPs to come.
Negative, Johanson. You're gonna
become a Marine right now.
- Fall out.
- Yes, sir.
Good morning, men.
I thought I'd lead you
through this exercise.
Couldn't find Gunny Highway, though.
I don't know where he went.
[SOLDIERS SHOUTING]
Good Lord, what was that?
- Sir, that's an AK-47 assault weapon.
- The preferred weapon of our enemy.
It makes a very distinctive sound
when fired at us, sir.
Yes, it does, doesn't it?
WOMAN: Good night, Aggie.
- Good night, Roy.
Hold up. I'll follow you home.
No, you go ahead. I've got some pains.
ROY: Oh, I got it.
- Not tonight you don't.
[ENGINE STARTS]
"Sensual communication,
meaningful...."
Panther piss.
Glad to know some things don't change.
You still know what a woman loves to hear.
Oh, I just happened to be
in the neighborhood.
I thought maybe you'd like to
sit down and talk.
Are you reading those magazines?
- What magazines?
- Those magazines.
Oh. Oh, those. No, I--
Somebody must have left them here.
- Who?
- Choozoo.
- He don't even know how to read.
- Quit being so stubborn.
Why don't you sit down
so we can talk?
I am not one of your troops
that can be bullied.
Jesus. Was being married
to me that bad?
Yes.
Platoon, ten-hut!
Thank you, gunny. What a fine morning
for a military exercise.
Today we will execute an ambush against
a numerically superior hostile force...
...by using cover, surprise,
interlocking fields of fire...
...and the natural aggressiveness
of a U.S. Marine.
Show me some poontang,
I'll show you an aggressive Marine.
We will provide Powers
and his elite fighting force...
...an accessible target
to sharpen their superior skills.
This will be facilitated by
the MILES gear each team wears.
As you know,
when one of our men is shot...
...these laser-sensitive vests
emit a beeping noise.
[BEEPING]
Excuse me, lieutenant, but are you
hinting that we don't fight back?
Yes, gunny. The major likes to use
the Recon Platoon as a training tool.
What happens when these men go
into combat, and they're not prepared?
They just get dead.
Well, yes, I see what you mean.
Have you talked this over
with Major Powers?
- Let's move them out, gunny.
- Are you coming with us, lieutenant?
No, gunny, I have a doctor's
appointment at 1100.
I hope it's nothing that will keep you
out of the next war.
Platoon, right face.
Sling arms.
Forward march.
- You sure Highway can run the ambush?
- He's the best with small unit tactics.
I doubt that.
Marines, today we're gonna
kick some recon ass.
[ALL YELL]
Platoon, ten-hut!
Right face. Forward march! Hut.
Man, when I joined the Corps, I thought
I was gonna be jumping out of planes...
- ...and fighting the enemy.
- This is the new, modern Marines.
- We just jump out of our heads.
- Only enemy we fight is boredom.
You hear that voice? It's calling me.
Hollywood.
[IN HIGH-PITCHED VOICE]
Stitch Jones is gonna be a rock 'n' roll star.
Don't forget your bros
when you make it.
Front row, center seat,
and all the girls I can't eat.
- Oh, I love leftovers.
- Mm-hm. Word.
- Unsling those rifles.
- What for? We're not supposed to win.
He watches too much prime time.
What was that?
You're dead, Marine.
You tripped on four booby traps.
Now we have to send out
a search party for your testicles.
Now, where the hell's your backup?
Profile.
What good are you back there?
Without cover, I get my ass blown off.
While you pump the neighbor's dog, we get
every swinging dick in this platoon killed.
That's what we're here for.
- What?
- We're here for that.
We've ambushed Powers three times,
always here. We know what we're doing.
Shit-for-brains, who says we're gonna
ambush Major Powers right here?
Didn't you hear Lt. Ring?
Major Powers wants us to die
in a loud, grotesque, military manner.
I don't give a fuck about Major Powers.
My job is to keep you men alive.
Now, let's move on.
We'll be coming to the ambush site
over the next hill.
Roger that.
It sure does help, knowing when
and where you're gonna be hit.
Easy. Give them a few more yards,
then we'll nail the coffin shut.
STITCH:
Chill out, here they come, man.
HIGHWAY [WHISPERS]:
Hit them now!
Now.
[CONTINUOUS GUNFIRE]
[RECON SOLDIERS YELLING]
[LAUGHING]
POWERS:
Cease fire!
You're in the wrong ambush site!
[LAUGHS]
Cease fire!
They're in the wrong ambush site!
STITCH:
Go, recon! Recon!
[RECON MEN LAUGHING AND SHOUTING]
[VESTS BEEPING]
STITCH: Too bad, suckers!
- Sergeant major!
CHOOZOO: What?
- Turn this damn thing off.
CHOOZOO: Makes a hell of a racket,
doesn't it, sir?
This man's usurped authority,
disregarded procedures...
...and ignored my personal directives
for over a week. Why, lieutenant?
- I thought the training--
- You're supposed to be an officer.
Look up that word in your
platoon leader's handbook.
Who gave you permission
to deviate from the training schedule?
I needed to evaluate my men, sir.
They're not your men, you arrogant son of
a bitch. They're the U.S. Marine Corps' men.
The 2nd Division's men.
The 8th Marines Regiment's.
In other words, they're my men,
and so are you. Get it?
The only thing I get is my ass shot off if
I have a platoon that doesn't know the job.
You'll follow my program,
no questions asked.
We go into combat tomorrow,
you'll plant half those men.
You did it on your own, didn't you?
I can't fix it if I don't know
what's broken.
Well, you make it easy.
RING:
Sir.
I gave the gunny permission
to freelance his-- I mean...
...the men, sir.
[SLAMS PHONE DOWN]
- Wait outside, Ring.
- Aye, aye, sir.
I'm gonna run you out of
the Corps, Highway.
And you know what's funny?
You're gonna do all the work.
Sooner or later, you'll disobey orders,
circumvent procedures again...
...or just get drunk.
You can't help it.
You're too old, too stupid...
...too prideful to change.
I'm gonna enjoy watching you fall.
Now, get out,
and send in that idiot, Ring.
He wants to see you, lieutenant.
- Sorry.
- No need to be.
Lieutenant?
Recon.
You'll let anybody in here, won't you?
Have one on the house
to ease your pain.
You wanna get drunk?
Howl at the moon?
Get us both busted back to low-ass,
no-rank, mud-rolling PFC?
I'm your man.
What are we, Chooz?
We're short-haired bastards with meat
cleavers for pricks and kerosene for blood.
Yeah. We're all of that,
that's for sure.
We're 0-1-1.
Say again?
Major Powers, one dark,
cloudy morning, said to me:
"Sergeant major, you're 0-1-1.
No wins.
One tie, Korea.
And one loss, Vietnam."
I mean, we lost the war,
but we won the battles.
I'm not gonna lose the next one
because my men aren't ready.
What are you gonna do?
Make them Marines.
[PHONE RINGS]
Stoney Jackson.
Best goddamn platoon sergeant...
...two mewling, short-pricked, pissant
little fuckers ever went to war with.
- Yep. Heartbreak Ridge.
- Heartbreak Ridge.
MARY:
Your C.O. called.
Your battalion just went on full alert.
God bless.
- I can't find my tent.
- Where's my poncho liner?
- Goddamn it! Who's got my web gear?
- Profile, that's my canteen.
Aponte better get his cartoon face
back here.
He's gonna do time for being AWOL.
People, let's have an equipment check.
Weapon?
Keep it simple. You've got your boots on.
You're gonna walk into combat. Let's go.
- Bullshit.
- Where's Aponte?
He's sick. Must be the beef.
I ain't feeling too good myself.
- You've eaten worse.
- Only when I'm shit-faced and silly.
Let's get going.
[MAN SHOUTING ORDERS INDISTINCTLY]
These DD 13-48 request forms
are not filled out properly.
We're going to approach this
in an orderly, proficient manner.
Yes, sir.
I want you to be sure each round of ammo
is counted and returned...
...in the same way it was received.
- I'll dot the I's and cross the T's.
- Sloppiness breeds inefficiency.
Your outfit could use some cleaning up,
gunny.
Sir, I want to issue my squad leader
some night vision glasses.
- I should've thought of that.
- It's not part of your T.O. & E.
I thought it--
Fill out the proper request forms
and send it through the chain of command.
Request forms?
Ten-hut.
At ease, men.
Major Malcolm Powers, sir.
Annapolis, class of ˉ71.
How are your men doing, major?
My men are ready to fight to the death
to protect our country, sir.
Well, let's hope
that won't be necessary.
Have we ever served together?
I don't know, sir.
Sergeant Major Choozoo and I...
...were in the 2nd Battalion
of the 7th in '68.
I had a rifle company
in the 1st Battalion.
We sure as hell chewed
some of the same dirt, sir.
That's for sure.
What's your assessment of this alert?
It's a clusterfuck.
[MEN SHOUTING IN DISTANCE]
Say again?
Marines are fighting men.
They shouldn't be sitting around...
...filling out request forms for equipment
they should already have.
Interesting observation, gunny.
Carry on, major.
OFFICER [OVER LOUDSPEAKER]:
Now hear this. Now hear this.
This is it. We're going to war.
OFFICER: This has been an emergency
deployment readiness exercise.
We are standing down.
The alert is canceled.
Damn it.
- Maybe next time, sir.
MAN 1: Gather your gear.
MAN 2:
You heard him. We're moving out!
[MUSIC PLAYS OVER RADIO]
[HUMMING]
STITCH [GRUNTS]:
Hey!
Aponte.
- Oh, him.
- Where is he?
What's wrong with you?
Nobody goes over the hill on me.
If you didn't have those fucking stripes on,
I'd kick your fucking ass!
Since I'm not into violence,
I'll refrain from kicking your ass.
I'm gonna give you
a rebate on your life.
Besides, who the hell is Aponte?
He ain't heavy
and he ain't my brother.
- Gunny Highway.
- That's right. Gunny Highway.
Come on in.
- Sorry, Aponte, I had to tell him.
- Don't worry. This is my wife.
Clean that up.
Look, gunny, I filled out
all the forms there are.
But what the Corps gives you
isn't enough for the family.
- So I took a job.
- You got a job?
Yeah.
- Did you want out of the Marine Corps?
- No. No way.
Then I guess we'll have to
cut through all the red tape B.S.
- Yeah, we are.
- Knock it off, will you?
Here. Here's a special fund.
Gunnery sergeants only.
Don't worry. You can pay it back.
- Here, you better take him. Jesus Christ.
- Thank you.
- What are you smiling at, shit bird?
- I knew you were Santa Claus.
You ever pull another play like that,
the only thing that'll beat you to the brig...
...is the headlights
of the ambulance you're on.
Yes, sir, Gunnery Sergeant Highway, sir!
[ENGINE STARTS]
Hey, yo, you can't leave the duke of cool!
This man has no social graces.
So....
Lureen down at the Palace
said you had the night off.
Lureen talks too much.
Can I buy you a beer?
Jesus.
You come stomping back
into my life after all this time...
...with no warning whatsoever.
Interfere with me at my place of work,
damn near start a brawl.
Almost lost me the only
crummy job I could find.
Then you show up here,
expecting me to...
...just smooth as silk, invite you in
for a sit-down and a smile.
It's always the same, Highway.
All balls, no brains.
- Is there something you're afraid of?
- Yes.
I'm afraid I'll dent that thick skull
of yours with this frying pan here.
It wouldn't be the first time for that,
now would it?
No.
[LAUGHS]
Nice place you have here.
Thanks. You want a glass?
Uh-uh.
Feet still bothersome?
Well, I hawk booze
five nights a week, you know?
There ain't no senior prom
looming on my horizon.
- To the old times.
- Mm.
Just as long as you don't say
"good times."
We had our share of those too,
didn't we?
I don't know. I can't think that far back.
How you feeling, babe?
Terrific. Absolutely couldn't feel better.
So...
...what brings you here?
I'm back with recon, back where I belong.
[CHUCKLES]
So?
It's different this time.
How?
I'm coming to the end of it.
I don't know where I go from here.
I just want it to end...
...as right as it was when I started.
You want some chips?
There's pretzels.
Yeah, thanks.
Fringe benefits of work.
Tell me something.
Did we mutually nurture each other?
I beg your pardon?
Did we communicate in a meaningful
way in our relationship?
Relationship?
Mm-hm.
[LAUGHS]
Hell, I thought we were married.
Well, I've been thinking
about the past lately...
...and I was just wondering
what went wrong.
With what?
With me...
...the Corps, with us.
That is so damn much like you.
You never could see that everything just
doesn't fit so neatly into right and wrong.
What else is there?
It isn't that simple.
I went by those rooms we rented
when we were first married.
Damn, they're small.
Yeah, well, they say everything
shrinks with age.
Tell me something.
What did you want out of our marriage?
[MOANS]
Well, we talked once
about an avocado ranch...
...about buying a house
with a barbecue in the back.
But then you would volunteer for every
goddamn war that came down the pike.
[MOANS]
Oh. Goddamn it!
- What's the matter?
- How could I be so stupid?
- What the hell are you talking about?
- You bastard.
- You changed tactics on me!
- What the fuck are you talking about?
Gave up the frontal assault,
tried to out-goddamn-flank me.
I am on to you.
I want you out of here right now!
Jesus Christ, you're not acting
very dignified for a mature woman.
Why, you old fucking Marine warhorse.
I'll show you dignified!
You get out of here! Get out of here!
Go on! Get the fuck out of here!
You better get your tail out of here
or I'll get mad!
Take that, you old fuck!
I never want to see your craggy
old face here again! You hear me?
Don't ever come back!
Ever, ever, ever! How dare you....
[OBJECTS CLATTERING]
She's as crazy as she's always been,
for chrissake.
AGGIE: You asshole!
- Shit.
Fuck.
Goddamn it.
I hate you, Highway!
AGGIE:
Fuck you!
[SINGS]
[LIGHT APPLAUSE]
Tonight's winner is...
[DRUM BEATS]
...Miss Sarita Dwayne!
SARITA: Oh!
EMCEE: What a gal.
Hey, yo, wait a minute, man.
That's bullshit. No.
- You're trying to rip me the hell off.
- Nobody likes a sore loser.
I'm an equal opportunity ass-kicker.
We gonna take a little vote.
All you all that voted
for Miss Banana Titties, say, "Yeah."
- No.
CROWD: Boo.
All y'all that voted for me,
say, "Rock the house!"
- Rock the house!
CROWD: Rock the house!
- Say, "Rock the house!"
What's up?
You all the faggot Mod Squad?
I don't play none of this jail
give-up-the-booty bullshit.
Yeah, right.
Don't ask for my autograph.
HIGHWAY: Yeah, you can rob me.
You can starve me...
...and you can beat me, and you can
kill me. Just don't bore me.
DEPUTY: I'm glad I could help.
CHOOZOO: I owe you dinner.
DEPUTY:
Sounds good.
CHOOZOO:
Try not to make a habit of that.
Jesus Christ.
Powers will thin-slice your prick and pitch
your gonads if he finds out about this.
STITCH: Sergeant major!
CHOOZOO: Who the hell are you?
Jones, sir. Second Battalion,
Recon Platoon.
Christ, Highway's platoon.
Snap to, marine. Give me a hand.
- We're like brothers.
- Like my grandmother.
Yes, well, I posted his bail.
- He needs you, Aggie.
- Ha-ha. Until the next war.
Good thing we got him out.
MARY:
Oh, shit.
Coffee.
Yeah, I always wanted
to check this place out.
- Look at all this history.
- Mary's served Marines from three wars.
How's he doing?
Aggie will put him back together again,
just like she always has.
Thank you, ma'am.
Highway's something else, huh?
High speed, low drag.
No one better to be with
if you're in a hot LZ.
Heartbreak Ridge.
It was the truth.
What's Heartbreak Ridge?
Now, listen. We have to understand
each other before...
...we go any further.
Are we going any further?
You're going to be out of the Corps soon.
But you're gung ho, through and through.
You always will be.
And there is no room
in my future for a...Marine.
I'm not sure I like
the way you say "Marine."
I can say Marine
any damn way I choose.
I earned that right.
That's right, you did.
I lived in a rat-hole when they
brought those boys home...
...in those flag-draped metal coffins.
I don't think I got a wink's sleep in '68.
Do you remember that year?
Yeah, I remember.
I'd wake up in the morning and turn on
the TV. I'd eat dinner in front of it...
...eyes glued, hoping to catch
a glimpse of you on the news...
...and then praying that I wouldn't.
And then I would crawl into bed and
I would wonder: Where were you?
What were you doing? Were you alive?
And I had no way of knowing.
I guess there's a lot of things that work
harder on a woman than being shot at.
I swear, the not knowing was the worst.
[SOBS]
Oh, I'm sorry.
[SOBBING]
That's all right, baby.
That's all right.
We went up and down that pile of dirt
for six days and six nights.
Fixed bayonet, hand-to-hand.
Fought them something fierce.
They gave back as good as they got.
Lots of men died.
We were with the 23rd Infantry.
We joined the Corps later. Hell,
we were even younger than you are.
Hmm. I never heard of no Heartbreak Ridge.
It ain't in any of the history books.
Just a little piece of war.
Place didn't even have a name,
just a number.
Stoney Jackson took one look
and said:
"If this don't kill us,
it'll surely break our hearts."
- Who's Stoney Jackson?
- Little Mary's husband.
He was our platoon sergeant.
He was the one who recommended Highway
for the Congressional Medal of Honor.
Gunny Highway won the C.M.H.?
He charged two machine gun nests by
himself. He didn't sleep for three days.
The final human wave he held off
almost single-handedly.
When it was over...
...there was me, Stoney Jackson,
Tom Highway.
We were the only ones still alive.
What happened to Jackson?
- He was killed at Khe Sanh in '68.
- Can I get you guys something to eat?
I can fix it in no time.
- No.
- Uh-- No, thank you, ma'am.
Excuse me, ma'am.
You don't happen to be...
...up and moving when
Gunny Highway leaves for the base?
I pour his coffee and lay out his things.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Platoon, ten-hut.
Right face.
Forward march!
Each platoon will proceed to the objective,
which in this case is the Battalion Bear Pit.
Whoever reaches it first
will get a 72-hour liberty.
Sir. It'd be an honor
if you'd accompany my platoon.
- Ugh.
- Thank you, staff sergeant.
Get out of your seats.
- Johanson, tighten up that harness.
- Gunny, I'm afraid of heights.
- So am I.
- You are?
Jumping out of a perfectly good aircraft
is not a natural act.
So let's do it right
and enjoy the view. Come on.
Let's move.
We made it. We're the first platoon
to reach the Bear Pit.
Not so quick, sir.
Oh, darn. First Platoon.
Major, it's Highway.
Damn.
Come on, men. Let's smoke them.
First Platoon, follow me!
[MEN SHOUTING]
Recon wins.
Gunny, you don't know your place.
First Platoon is the victor.
I'd say we have ourselves a dilemma, sir.
Sergeant Major, I order you
to declare 1st Platoon the winner.
Sir, that wouldn't be fair.
What do you propose
to resolve this situation?
Matchup.
Okay, men, get them off.
[MEN SHOUTING]
Get your shit off, let's go.
MAN 1: Yeah! Yeah!
MAN 2: Come on!
[CHATTERING AND SHOUTING]
Come on!
Come on, shithead!
Get them out!
Come on, you fucking dickhead!
- I got him! I got him! I got him!
- Pull!
Come on!
We've got him! First Platoon!
BOTH:
Aah!
Recon!
Recon! Recon!
Sergeant major, 1st Platoon wins!
I don't see it that way, major.
You're out of order.
First Platoon is king of the pit.
- How do you figure?
- Your man cheated.
- I say he improvised.
- He cheated!
He adapted. He overcame.
There's only one way to settle this.
Platoon sergeants, front and center.
Remember, sergeant,
I'm leading your platoon today.
Old man, it's time for somebody
to put you in your place.
Come on, major!
[MEN SHOUTING]
MAN:
Let's go, gunny!
[ALL CHEERING]
Man, it felt great beating
Major Powers' elite fighting unit!
[ALL CHEER]
I've been bitten
by every bug known to mankind.
No, these bumps make you look
like you got muscles.
- I bet I have poison ivy.
- Man, you can get permanent light duty...
...for all the crud on your body.
Your dream come true.
You won't have to do this bullshit no more.
Fuck you.
I'm getting pretty good at this.
MEN:
Whoa!
This man must be sick,
ladies and gentlemen.
I'll tell you sick.
Gunny Highway is the sickest individual
it's been my sorry pleasure to come across.
Order today and get this record
from Recon Records. Songs like:
- "Highway, You Sick Individual."
- Yeah.
- "Polish My Weapon, I'll Polish Yours."
- That's my song.
- "Bionic, Bionic Marine."
- Bionic Marine.
- That's it.
- Do that one.
[SINGING]
Well, he kicked a lot of ass
At a place called Heartbreak Ridge
Don't fuck with Scarface Highway
Baddest jarhead that there is
He's a bad psycho mother
Bionic Marine
A leatherneck lifer
Who likes the barracks clean
- He kicked Powers in the ass
- Webster upside the head
If you fuck with this sick mother
Then you gonna end up dead
He's a fire-pissing jarhead
Bionic Marine
Salty dog don't wear nothing
But Marine Corps green
- Ain't got time to shit or shower
- Ain't got time to smoke a cig
I said don't fuck with Gunny Highway
Or you'll end up in the brig
[ALL CHEER]
Tell you something else, man.
Highway won the Congressional
Medal of Honor at Heartbreak Ridge.
- Check that out. Check that out!
- C.M.H.?
I knew he was bad, but not that bad.
Agent Powers wants statements
from each and every one of you.
What kind of statements?
Gunnery Sergeant Highway
used live ammunition...
...with unauthorized weapons
on the training exercise.
Says who?
I thought you guys
didn't like Highway.
I heard that AK-47 fire
coming from your A.O.
Don't you boys want to go back to the
way it was? Nobody fucking with you?
It seems to me that no one's gonna
fuck with us the way things are now.
There's weekend liberty
in it for all of you.
I'll start with you.
I got nothing to say.
You.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
This is gonna go hard on y'all
if y'all don't cooperate.
We ain't got nothing to say to you,
Webster.
Why don't you take your ass back
to that faggot 1st Platoon of yours...
[IMITATING HIGHWAY]
...and don't go away mad, just go away.
You've been told.
Bye, Webster.
[ALL LAUGH]
Yeah!
HIGHWAY: I hate social functions.
CHOOZOO: You're gonna love it.
Your presence is requested at
the M.A.U. commander's open house.
Full military dress.
- Piss on that.
- You will be there, Sergeant Highway.
Stand tall and look sharp so they can
see a hero who isn't bleeding to death.
HIGHWAY: Let's find the bar.
- Good idea.
- How are you this evening? Thanks.
- How are you?
Privileged to greet
a Medal of Honor winner.
Thank you, sir.
Run into any clusterfucks lately?
No. Not lately, sir.
Thank you for stopping by.
Enjoy the party.
I love watching the brass snap to
attention when they see that ribbon.
What do you do at a party like this?
Stick out your pinkie?
Just don't unzip
and stick Old Blue out.
Didn't J.J. Johnson do that
at a WAVE party in San Diego?
No, that was me. J.J. mooned
the ARVN general at China Beach.
Here, let's drink a toast to J.J.
and all the pieces of him we couldn't find.
Funniest guy I ever met.
One thing about a party like this,
the conversation's so adult.
I think I'm gonna head for
the back door of this place.
And lose all this joy?
You won't be brokenhearted if I cut in,
will you?
I'll get over it.
I'm gonna see what the chow's like.
Would you like to dance?
- Yeah. What are you doing here?
- I'm still on the mailing list.
HIGHWAY:
Hmm.
- Yeah?
AGGIE: Yeah.
[BAND PLAYS ROMANTIC TUNE]
Did I by any chance
give you that perfume?
[LAUGHS]
What's so funny?
I was just thinking...
...this reminds me of the senior prom
and that chaperone with the ruler.
"Agnes Anne, you keep 8 inches
of daylight...
...between you and that young man
you're dancing with."
[LAUGHS]
Yeah, I do remember that.
Wasn't that the...?
The first night we ever...?
Yes. Yes, it was.
Agnes Anne, you were a wild creature,
I must say.
What do your magazines say about that?
I don't know, I haven't gotten to that part.
- Are you still reading them?
- Affirmative.
And what do they say about ex-wives?
Not too much.
Just that the sex is great...
...because you don't have to establish
a relationship or be meaningful.
[CHUCKLES]
- You really are trying to understand us?
- The best I can, yeah.
Is that because you can't be a Marine
anymore and you've got no place to go?
I shouldn't have said that. I'm sorry.
It's all right. We've known each other
too long to run away...
...just over a little thing like
tearing each other's guts out.
Tom, I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have said that. It just--
It just never seems to work out
between you and me.
- With her husband.
- I see.
- I'm having a great time.
- It's a whole family gathering.
I've been thinking a little bit about
that avocado ranch we talked about.
Tom, Roy has asked me to marry him.
What did you say?
MEYERS [ON MIC]:
Your attention, please.
The 22nd Marine Amphibious Unit's
alert status has just been upgraded.
All officers and staff NCOs will
immediately return to their units.
Thank you.
[CROWD MURMURING]
What's the deal?
Is this another bullshit alert?
We're going to war, men.
Mother of Jesus.
We're gonna assist in an operation
on the island of Grenada...
...to rescue American citizens there.
The island of what?
Grenada, a Caribbean island
also known as the Isle of Spice.
It's 86 nautical miles
northeast of Venezuela.
Our mission is to helocast into a small
bay on the west side of the island...
...and recon in advance of the Marines.
I can't do that, man.
I forgot my suntan oil.
Come on, it's time to earn your pay.
Let's move it.
Pick it up. Let's go.
OFFICER [OVER LOUDSPEAKER]:
Now hear this. Now hear this.
Flight deck, prepare to launch helo.
Prepare to launch helo.
Over there!
Your glasses.
Get ready.
HIGHWAY [OVER RADIO]:
Choozoo, do you read me?
This is Highway. Do you read me?
I want your platoon to recon
toward the university.
HIGHWAY:
Stay low around Powers, you hear?
See you when it's over.
[GUNFIRE]
Spread out. Spread out.
Jesus, what was that?
- AK-47. It has a distinctive sound.
- Proceed swiftly and with caution.
Get that 60 going around the corner.
Cover my ass.
Highway's crazy, man.
[YELLING IN SPANISH]
APONTE:
They pulled out, lieutenant!
All right, Aponte.
Slowly.
Damn.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[SCREAMS]
Cubans. Mm.
Three-man recon team.
Better spread out. I'm sure
they got buddies around here.
Let's go.
Spread the fuck out. Let's go.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Okay. Go ahead.
[CHATTERING CONTINUES]
[GUNFIRE]
[GRUNTS]
We forgot the hot dogs. I'll go back
to New York and get the hamburgers.
Are you as good with engines
as your mouth?
- Jones is the name, hot-wire's the game.
- Get on that cat.
Get on that cat with him.
- You set? Let's do it.
- Let's go.
Swede. Get up there with that M-60.
[ENGINE WHINING]
[ENGINE STARTS]
Yeah!
I'm the ayatollah of rock 'n' roll-ah!
Stay right there, sucker.
Whoo!
[GUNFIRE]
HIGHWAY:
Stay low.
[ENEMY SOLDIERS YELLING]
Jesus, please forgive me.
Come on, let's go.
Let them know who you are
so no friendlies get hurt.
Hello, happening hostages,
I'm Stitch Jones, Mr. Funkadelic.
Try U.S. Marine, shithead.
RECON MARINE:
It's all clear!
United States Marines!
Ah!
HIGHWAY:
You've improved.
Goddamn it, gunny!
[GASPS]
Uh-- U.S. Marines, ma'am.
[HOSTAGES SCREAM
- U.S. Marines!
- Everybody all right?
[HOSTAGES CHEERING]
You know what they say:
A behind is a terrible thing to waste.
Delta Company said they'd give us
surfboards and let us go down to the beach.
One of those students kissed me
four times. I think I'm in love.
- Was he good-looking?
- It was a girl.
Clean your weapons,
check your ammo.
All secured. No casualties,
no sign of enemy.
Very good. I want some pictures
before we wrap this mission.
We encountered heavy resistance
along the way.
Probably local fanatics.
Negative. Cuban regulars
with Russian rifles.
That type of data
has already been factored in.
CHOOZOO: Battalion.
- Go ahead.
Big Daddy says to get off your fat ass
and get back in the war. His words, sir.
Says to recon that hill.
Some flier thinks he saw some armor.
- You're full of good news.
- You're too ugly to live forever.
Gunny, recon that hill, but wait for Foxtrot
Company before launching any assault.
Now, you stay in contact.
Shall I send back data, sir,
or is that already factored in?
Move out.
Powers has the hots for you. Watch
your back. Could be wedding bells.
All right, let's move out, recon.
Form up.
[HOSTAGES CHEERING]
All right, let's go.
Come on.
Keep moving.
Careful, guys.
[GUNFIRE]
Shit!
RING: Let's move!
- Get down. Get down!
RING:
Get in the building!
No!
[YELLING]
MAN:
Move it!
RING:
Get in the building! Go!
Bad mistake, coming in here like this.
- It's my fault.
- Apologize to their mothers.
Jesus, gunny!
[GUNFIRE CONTINUES]
Lay some steel on those targets.
Collins, Aponte!
Radio battalion, see if we can
get some air support.
Yo, gunny, I think Profile's dead.
[EXPLOSION AND GUNFIRE CONTINUE]
[SIGHS]
Don't let him die, gunny.
That's not up to me.
Come on, stay down, everyone.
Let's go.
HIGHWAY: How you doing?
- I'm okay.
- Doing better than Profile.
- I can still fight.
- We gonna make it out?
- Why, got a date?
You never know.
[GUNFIRE AND EXPLOSION]
Gunny, I got Profile killed.
It was his time. When it's your time,
I don't give a damn how fast you run.
- I could've gotten them all killed.
- But you didn't.
Just don't make the same mistake twice.
Right.
I think I figured out a way to call in an air
strike if we can find where this line's cut.
Jones!
- That's the name, loving's the game.
- Thanks for volunteering.
- Say what?
- Get up and find where the line's cut.
Come on, don't stand there, damn it.
I wish I was back in New Jersey,
watching The Flintstones.
I hate this bullshit.
[GUNFIRE]
Do you know who you're shooting at?
I'm the ayatollah of rock 'n' roll-ah.
Probably don't speak no English.
Banana-eating, bean-farting motherfuckers.
Hello? Hello?
- It works!
- Damn right, it works.
Almost got my ass shot off for Ma Bell.
Hello? Operator?
I'd like to make an emergency
long-distance call...
...to Camp Lejeune, North Carolina.
Collect.
What?
Anybody got a credit card?
They won't make collect calls.
Have no fear, Stitch is here.
I never go to combat without my plastic.
Yes.
It's 6-6-0...
...5-5-8...
...0-7-1-1.
Camp Lejeune.
Are you for real?
Grid 2-1 -9...
...6-3-2-1 -8--
- Did they get it?
- I don't know. The phone went dead.
Give me that.
Gunny, where are you going?
They don't see our marker,
we're in real trouble.
You don't know
if the transmission got through.
Well, I'll have to improvise, sir.
Shit.
[GUNFIRE]
Shit, Highway's been hit!
What are we gonna do, sir?
Let's go.
[ENEMY SOLDIER YELLS]
[CHEERING]
Don't die, man.
Gunny!
Jones....
Just because we're holding hands...
...doesn't mean we're gonna take warm
showers till the wee hours of the morning.
You hear me?
- Sucker, I thought you was dead!
- Wishful thinking.
Well, lieutenant,
what are we waiting for?
All right, you devil dogs.
- Let's take this fucking hill!
ALL: Oorah!
MAN 1: Let's go!
MAN 2: Go, go!
[SIGHS]
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING IN DISTANCE]
[SHOUTING IN SPANISH]
[SHOUTING IN DISTANCE]
[GUNFIRE]
Go!
All right, get them out of there!
[SHOUTING IN SPANISH]
Put your hands up!
- Bunker secure, sir!
- Thank you.
- Corporal Jones!
- Yes, sir.
- Move them out.
- You heard the man! Move out!
[MARINES YELLING]
Move it, ladies!
[VEHICLE APPROACHING]
Just what the hell
do you think you were doing?
Just enjoying the view, sir.
Well, you disobeyed a direct order.
I told you to stay in contact
and not to take this hill without me.
Get on your feet, Highway!
Will all due respect, sir, you're beginning
to bore the hell out of me.
[AIRCRAFT APPROACHING]
- Who's in charge here?
- I am, sir. Major Malcolm Powers.
Did you lead this assault?
Lieutenant Ring and Gunnery Sergeant
Highway disobeyed a direct order.
I told them to wait for support,
but they still charged up this hill.
Why?
We're paid to improvise, sir.
Overcome, adapt.
I gave the order to take this hill.
Ring, this is gonna ruin your career.
- Are you new to the infantry, major?
- Yes, sir. Come over from Supply.
- Were you good at that?
- Yes, sir.
Then stick to it. You're a walking
clusterfuck as an infantry officer.
This is a Marine amphibious unit.
My men are hard-chargers.
Ring and Highway took
a handful of young fire-pissers...
...exercised some personal initiative,
and kicked ass!
- Good work, lieutenant.
- Thank you, sir.
See that some of those students
are escorted back to Cherry Point.
Aye, aye, sir.
Well, you're dismissed.
[ENGINE STARTS]
What the hell are you two sorry-assed
individuals looking at? Get out of my LZ.
BOTH:
Semper Fi.
Oorah.
Well, Chooz, I guess we're not
0-1 -1 now, huh?
[MARCHING BAND PLAYING]
[CROWD CHEERING]
- There's my family.
STITCH: All right!
- Got anybody here?
- No, but it's a beautiful day...
- ...and your boy Stitch is ready to play.
- Give them hell.
Yeah, I'm gonna do that. Definitely.
Like I said, it's a beautiful day and
Stitch Jones is ready to play, you know?
- Anytime, man.
- All right, big guy.
You'll be a civilian soon.
You can let your hair long, sleep late...
...and become an asshole
rock 'n' roll star.
Sergeant Major Choozoo
gave me re-up papers.
And you signed them?
Tell you the truth, gunny,
I'm a better Marine than a singer.
You're also a lot dumber
than I thought you were.
What about you?
No, I've had it. No room
in this man's Corps for me now.
Besides, they've got you.
WOMAN:
Michael!
Hi, honey!
He-hey!
I guess all this marching bands and
parades and shit is old stuff to you?
Tell you the truth, this is the first time.
Well, well, well. There are my ladies.
Well, hey, gunny...
...duty calls.
[WOMEN YELLING]
STITCH:
What's happening?
[STITCH LAUGHS]
[SIGHS]
[ENGLISH SDH]